[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Well, good morning, good afternoon, and
good evening. Welcome to Living Manor
Church. Thank you so much for joining us
today for worship service. Um, I am
Patrice Salisser. I am the secretary
here at Living Mana Church. And you
know, whenever you see me, that means
sister is taking some much needed rest.
And as a matter of fact, this is their
anniversary weekend. So, we definitely
want to make sure uh we share some love
in the comments and more about that in a
few minutes. But I want you guys to take
a minute to right now as you are seeing
me watch you're watching me live. Please
make sure you share this live. Please
make sure you share the mana. We are
here to worship together on this
beautiful Sabbath day. Um, I'm actually
uh coming to you live from Pennsylvania
and we're starting to see a little bit
of fall starting to peek through the
curtain and I'm so excited because it's
been extremely hot. Um, so we are
looking forward to just the beginnings
of the changing of the leaves and um,
we're excited about just new beginnings
and and beautiful transitions here in
the Eastern Corridor. But right now I
want to make sure not only are you
sharing you are liking every time you
hit the live on the like button on the
live you are definitely increasing the
opportunity for us to reach more people
for the kingdom and also you participate
as well. You become our digital
disciple. So uh thank you guys so much
for tuning in. Please make sure please
you make sure you also if you're not a
subscriber then what are you doing?
Please make sure you subscribe to the
Living Mana online church channel. We
are so excited about that. And I want to
give a greetings and shout out to our
Power of the Lamb viewers. You guys are
always locked in with us every single
Sabbath. We see you on the technical
team. You're always engaged and we are
so excited about that. And if this is
your first time like how did I stumble
across this this channel? How did I
stumble across this church? It is
definitely by divine appointment. So,
please make sure if this is your first
time, please put a one the number one in
the comments in the chat. We've got so
many wonderful uh I'm going to call us
our digital ushers welcoming you. Our
members are welcoming you and sending
loves and hugs. And also, if you have a
prayer request, it's not too early. You
can also submit your prayer requests in
the chat. And our prayer warriors are
live active right now. They have been
praying even before we even became on
live and praying to cover you and
praying to cover this service today. And
so they are looking for your prayers to
pray and come alongside you to lift your
petitions up to the Lord. So in the
meantime um there we are going to have a
rebroadcast of a wonderful Sabbath
school that was done by Rick and Cindy
Mercer. But the message is live from
Pastor Myers. We are, listen, he's not
going to leave us out here with no fresh
bread and no fresh mana. And so, you
know, the prayer team is up on deck,
Brother Terry, Sister Ammer, and they've
got some surprise guests for you today.
So, please sit back, relax, enjoy the
mana, enjoy the service, and I'll see
you for divine worship service.
So, we would like to welcome He already
said Rick, but Rick and Cindy Mercer uh
to Living Mana Church.
And there there they are. Yay.
>> Oh my goodness. It's so good to see you
again.
>> It's so good to see both of you. We met
Did you meet them first or did we meet
them together in Oklahoma? It was a
prayer conference.
>> Yeah.
>> Tulsa. Tulsa. Oklahoma at Advent. Uh,
Adventist Fellowship. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Yes. I remember
>> had a good time there that weekend.
>> Yes. And
>> and that's where the picture was taken.
>> Yes. It was I know this picture.
>> I agree with you.
>> When you sent me that picture, Cindy,
last night I saw the picture and you
wouldn't have said, "Oh, that's Yeah, we
have Ivore. Uh, a picture of Rick and
Ivore." Because at first I didn't know
that was you. Like that was a long time
ago. Like
>> it was
>> Yeah, that was a long time ago.
>> I was skinny then. I was I didn't say
it. I did not say that.
But the thing is, guys, he purposely is
bigger now. Like he people, you know,
some people get bigger and they don't do
it on purpose.
>> No, it it was it was literally a a
perfect picture. And so we're we're
we're so glad it's on our our website
and we just left it there because we
love it. So
>> that's so cool. That is so cool. We're
so happy that you guys are here. Uh Rick
and Cindy have also done ministry with
us with Army. They've spoke at I think
two armies I believe in New York and in
North Carolina. And so it was just a
blessing to always do ministry um with
Rick and Cindy. And you will see why
because they're so such amazing people
>> and passionate.
>> And passionate. Yes. Um first I want to
say what you guys are currently doing
now and then we'll jump into your
testimony. Let us know just let our
audience know who who you what you guys
are first.
Uh, I'll go first. Rick Mercer. I'm the
ministerial director right now in in
Oklahoma, the Oklahoma Conference. And
Cindy, my wife, is the prayer
coordinator for the Oklahoma Conference.
>> Amen. You know, I did not know that.
>> We are We are going a lot of places
right now. Um, we go well local
obviously. We spend a lot of time just
saturating our conference with prayer.
Doing a lot of prayer weekends,
>> doing um just prayer emphasis weekends
and and also doing quite a fair share of
uh like marriage and family relationship
>> programs. So wonderful. God is good.
>> God is so good. Well, congratulations on
your guys' new positions. Um I
>> How long because I think the last time
we spoke you were pastoring. Yeah. You
were pastoring in was it North Carolina?
I think North Carolina.
>> We were We were in the Carolina
Conference.
>> But we went to Northwest Arkansas. We
were in Arkansas, Louisiana for what?
Four years.
>> Yeah. And in January January 2022 is
when we moved to Oklahoma City.
>> Now, you're from Oklahoma.
>> Well, that's where you
>> We're from We're from LA, remember?
No, I'm not remembering that. But okay,
>> we're gonna get back into the story.
>> We're we're from we're from lower
Arkansas. That's LA. And I was born in
Louisiana if you can't tell accent.
>> I was about to say I'm from California,
too. But we talk very different.
>> I had to rip you a little bit. So,
>> yes, that's what I'm remembering. You
guys are so much fun. So much fun. We
were even remember we were like
sweetmates like when we were in New York
we shared that.
>> Oh yeah that was great. That was fun.
>> We had our girls who Yes. That was fun.
That was fun.
>> Fun.
>> So yes. Um so Stardust. Who wants to go?
I think Cindy you have to go first.
>> I let let Cindy go first. It's start.
>> Yes.
>> Well stop us if we're talking too much
or you know we don't want
>> I'm the time keeper. Don't just don't
worry. We got good deal. So, you know,
our story um could begin a lot of
different places, but we'll begin from
we'll just like kind of come out with a
gusto. Um Rick and I had a a blind date
and there's some backstory there, but we
decided to go out and he he showed up at
my house one night. I didn't have social
media then, so I couldn't check him out,
you know, which would have been kind of
nice. But here he is, you know, cold
call at the door and I opened the door.
was like, "Whoa, this guy is gorgeous."
>> And I mean, his eyes were just piercing
and you know, he just it was great. I
was like, "Okay, well, this is good so
far." You know, aesthetically, he checks
off my list. And so, we had a really
good evening, a good good time together.
And I was thinking, okay, this is the
girl who didn't want a relationship, but
now all of a sudden, I'm like, whoa,
really liking this guy. and hoping he
would ask me for another date. You know,
that's why I was hoping the evening
would end. But we get back to my house
and we begin to, you know, talk some
more and he he kind of goes in with this
stare at me and I thought, okay, here it
comes. It's like, you want to go out
again? And so instead of asking a
question, Atanti, he asked the question
and he said, "Will you marry me?"
>> And that's the end of our testimony. We
hope you guys have a good rest of your
Sabbath. Um, may the Lord richly bless
you. How long y'all been married?
>> We just celebrated 26 years by the grace
of God.
>> Yes.
>> Congratulations. Wow. Yeah. Wow.
>> But there's a lot.
>> There's a lot in between. Yeah.
>> Oh, there's a lot of in between. Yes.
>> You better jump ahead and tell them.
>> But, you know, here we were. You know,
he asked me to marry him and I was like,
okay, sure. I said yes.
>> Wow.
>> And so you
>> And you weren't And and Cindy, you
weren't intoxicated or anything. You
were
>> No. No. No. No.
>> You were sober.
I was completely sober.
>> Well, the lemon must have intoxicated me
in my water.
>> On the way home, I was driving on the
way home. I live about 35 miles south of
there and and it hit me that I was a CPA
at the time and it was right in
>> March 20th. Yeah.
>> And I was at that time I was working
around the clock and and I said, "I
ain't got time to get married right
now." And I called her back. I said, "I
can't do it right now." So, we waited
>> Oh, yeah. We waited a whopping six weeks
and got married on May 3rd
>> after tax season.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> You guys, it was
>> it was a whirlwind romance meeting his
family, my family. And
>> I was going to say I was just going to
say I'm sure your family just thought
you both were crazy, but they went
>> of course they still do think we're
crazy, but they love us, so that's good.
But um and we were a blended family and
so we that's why I believe God has used
that to allow us to help others because
he had two little boys at the time that
were six and seven and I had a little
boy that was two and of course we have
one together now. So we have four boys
and they're all grown and adulting. So
yeah,
>> which is all that we ask for for our
kids is to Yes.
>> finally get them to be adulting. Okay.
So you guys got married?
>> Yep. got married. Then what happened?
>> What happened, Rick?
>> Yeah. You know, um when I first met
Cindy,
she was everything that I could ever ask
for later. I mean, I was not planning on
that. I didn't It was a blind date. Like
you said, this totally caught me off
guard. I was not expecting this, but
when I It was love at first sight. Made
in love. And at that time I had been I
had I had only been married like a year
and a half long enough to have you know
two sons and but most of my life and I
was I was probably
>> Hey Rick, can you can you can you
maybe speak up a little bit louder?
They're having a little bit difficulty.
>> Yeah, we hear Cindy really well then we
hear you but you're just a little bit
softer.
>> Okay. I was
>> Yeah, that's I was okay. Can you hear me
better now? That's good.
>> Okay. We were um I I had been single for
a long time and I lived a a single
lifestyle and I lived I I worked hard. I
I had a you know I had the CPA firm but
I also raised commercial poultry. Had a
I was a business owner. I had I raised
about a million chickens a year for for
a company. And and so
>> did he wait did you say did you say a
million chickens a year?
>> Yeah. He did.
>> Yeah. Wow. And and so but with my
lifestyle though, what I did is I I
could just I just I partied a lot
>> and and so I worked really hard, but I
played really hard. But when I met
Cindy, I said, "That's this is it." You
know, I'm shutting everything else out,
>> and she's all I need, and this is what
I've been waiting for. It's time to
settle down.
>> And yeah, and I did
>> my thoughts. Exactly. pastor e
really really really good for about a
month
and then and then the old me started
coming surgicing again you know other
words I tried to do it on my own
>> yeah God bless you Rick I tried to do it
on my own strength and so
>> but I didn't know the old hymn I only
knew the woo you know you know whatever
sweet thing wants sweet thing gets Rick
Mercer you like all all in, you know,
I'm your man, you know, that's all I
knew. And so it was a whiplash
>> to
>> a month in when he started
>> Yes.
>> turning backwards. Okay.
>> Yeah. And we limped along for several
months. Me knowing something was wrong.
You know, I always say the gut doesn't
lie. I mean,
>> true.
>> You know, there was something going on.
Couldn't put my finger on it. Very
disturbing. He was coming in later,
later. And I'm thinking, hey, I'm his
new bride. He should want to be home.
What have I done wrong? I started just
um you know, putting on a lot of stuff
on my own self that I should have never
had to do, but uh it's what we do. You
know, we cope. We do those defensive
things. And so, I didn't know what was
going on. And five months later, we we
separated.
>> We were like,
>> "Yeah, as far as I knew, it was over and
it was never coming back." Yeah.
>> Okay. Okay. Wow.
>> Um,
>> everything happened quickly.
>> Yeah. So, it it came quick, but it it
Yeah.
>> Yeah. And I'd like to say here, I had
good intentions from the bottom of my
heart when I said I loved her. I did
love her.
>> And and I and I really wanted to settle
down. And I look back now, God was
wanting to rescue me. But but we all
know that this takes Jesus.
>> And and uh and I did not have Jesus in
my life. That was what was missing. that
empty spot that I was trying to fill for
everything else.
>> And and I did have Jesus in my life, but
not like I thought I did. Not like I
knew I needed to have. I was kind of on
the fence a little bit to be honest.
>> Um really from the time we got married,
I I wasn't going to church as much and
>> I knew that I needed to be, but I
wasn't. But you know what happens when
right
>> we hit that rock bottom or we hit
desperation? What do we do? We cry out
if we, you know, I grew up in church my
entire life. So, I immediately cried out
to God at that point.
>> I need you. I need help really bad, you
know, and that was um
>> that was a challenge because what
happened in the time we separated, uh we
don't have time to unpack it all here,
but um the bottom line is is that his
life was spiraling out of control. Uh it
was a dark dark period for him during
our separation. Uh it was a dark period
for me, but I was trying to come out of
it. I was trying to get closure. I filed
for divorce. He he wouldn't sign the
divorce papers. I had no closure. I had
more question marks than answers. And it
was a pretty crazy time,
>> honestly.
>> So yeah. So I mean we I mean we have
some time. I can tell you our living
mana audience likes to We're pretty
transparent here. So they like to know.
>> Awesome. We love it. We love it. They
like to know because because it helps.
There's a lot of people that are in
similar there may be people I shouldn't
say a lot but there should there are
people in similar situations and that at
least are just kind of
>> you know not knowing. So like because
when you want to say because we know now
you've been married 26 years but how
dark how dark was dark?
>> So Rick why don't I think you should
share what was really going on with you.
We all want to know
>> dark is dark. It was really dark.
Um it was the most horrible time in my
life. I look back now and Satan was
trying to destroy me. Um I had um you
know I had I mentioned that I that I
lived a a pretty fast lifestyle. Well
included in that in that lifestyle was
was a drug called cocaine.
>> And and it started it started um you
know you I didn't look like somebody
that used cocaine. I dress similar to
what I'm dressed like now. Uh I didn't I
I I had people that worked for me. I
didn't look like somebody that was
cocaine on cocaine, but I would do it on
the weekends is when I would do that
that lifestyle. I drink I drink casually
every day, you know, socially every day.
And that was just a lifestyle I was in.
But when Cindy and I when Cindy and I
got married, what happened is I quit I
stopped hanging out with the people on
the weekends that that I used to run
around with. I mean, we would we live I
lived in South Arkansas. We would go to
Memphis, we would go to we New Orleans,
we'd go to Florida, we do those kind of
things on the weekends and and uh and it
was nothing uncommon for me to do those
kind of things. But when when when uh we
got married, I quit running around the
crowd that I was running around and I
talked to
>> and I started I started hanging out with
some like more of the local guys,
>> good old country boys.
>> Good old local guys. And Her drug of
choice was a drug called crystal meth.
>> Oh yes. Oh man,
>> there's your dark side.
>> That's dark.
>> It got really dark. Uh it got dark. I
went I went from zero to to 100 miles an
hour really fast with crystal meth. It
was the drug, you know. I had played
with drugs my whole life. And no problem
with me. I was able to to function with
them. I could I could pick them up. I
could set them down. Uh nothing. But
with crystal meth, it got a hold on me.
It got a grip on me and everything else
uh was everything else took a second
place, including my my marriage. I
walked in one day and I said, you know,
I told S, I just don't want to be
married no more.
>> And and then and my the same my clients,
I had over 400 clients that I took care
of. I did anything from their payroll to
payroll taxes to audit work for them to
financial counseling. I had a a wide
variety as a public accountant and I I I
I I just walked away from my CPA firm. I
just didn't have time for it no more.
Just didn't have left 400.
>> It was all about the drug.
>> It was all about the drug. It completely
took over my life. It was the darkest
period of my whole life. Cindy and I
were separated for almost a year
>> and and I had uh I I it's really
difficult for me to even think about how
dark it really got. Satan was trying to
destroy me. It was only by the grace of
God I'm alive right now.
>> And I'm alive because of this lady
sitting right here beside me. Uh that
that that uh she didn't give up. She she
she stayed in contact. she she keep
calling and eventually we got we got uh
we got back together through a chain of
circumstances
uh that uh
>> that's a good way to put it.
>> Let's hear about those chain of
circumstances. So
>> because you because I want to take you
back because you went to file for
divorce but he wouldn't sign. So Rick,
even though you said you didn't want to
be married anymore, you still didn't
sign the papers. So I think that was
that the Holy Spirit like telling you
like you didn't know that was the Holy
Spirit but
>> you weren't.
>> I think you're right. God this you know
he God is he's like I've heard one guy
say
>> wait wait wait Rick hold on Cindy.
>> Yeah
>> it what ear are you wearing your your
earpod in?
>> Left.
>> Could you put it in the in the right ear
so that the microphone is closer to Rick
when he speaks?
>> I can try except he has my right one.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh.
>> So,
>> I think to him,
>> um, that could help. Or if you guys
switch
>> or if you Yeah, if you um
>> Okay, we can switch. Hold on real quick.
>> No, no, no. Just switch places.
>> No, that's what No, no, no, no, no. Just
switch.
>> We were saying switch places.
>> No, no, keep that. Let's see if
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Is that better?
>> Let's see now. Go ahead,
>> Rick. You talk.
Facebook.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So, Cindy Cindy stayed in touch.
Uh, she kept reaching out and then and
then you said you want to hear the rest
of the story there. So, go ahead, Cindy.
>> They said they think it's because you
speak fast.
You only know how funny that was. Um,
we're from Arkansas. We can't say
anything fast. It's like hello takes
five minutes. Um,
man,
>> I forgot how much of a I forgot how much
of a comedian you were.
>> I can only laugh now because God's been
so good to us. But there was no laughing
going on. Of course, you know, at that
time, um, can you hear can you hear me?
Okay,
>> we can hear you. Everybody's great and
better. Perfect.
>> Good.
>> But he glosses over this little spot.
But um during that year, very dark year,
I did hear that he was doing better. I
kept in contact with his sister, who was
also one of the people that connected us
for our blind date. And and I was um
checking in and she says, "You know,
Rick's doing a lot better. Uh my mom and
dad kind of been keeping their thumb on
him a little bit more and things like
that." And there's a lot of, you know,
story there. But I said, "Okay, that's
great." Well,
about May after we've been we separated
in September, right, of 97. So about May
of 98, it's about time for us to
celebrate our first anniversary and
we're not together and it's all sad and
everything. Well, my grandfather had
passed away and I was at work at the
operating room and I ran into the locker
room and I saw a piece lily with a big
red bow on it and I thought, "Wow, who's
that from?" And I pulled the card off
and it it was from Rick and the boys.
>> I thought, man, I know he didn't send
that. His mother probably did, but okay.
It was a nice gesture,
>> but it touched my heart. So, I picked up
the phone to call him and thank him,
which he never would answer the phone.
He would always say,
you know, connection's bad. Can't talk
right now or wouldn't answer,
>> but he answered this time and I wanted
to let him have it. That's I I wanted to
vomit out all how the bad stuff, all the
stuff he put me through because all my
friends were watching like, "Girl, I'm
so excited for you when we first got
married." And and now I'm like,
>> what is going on?
>> And and it had been really bad because I
mean I we're giving you a lot of like
little scatter shots here, but
>> yeah,
>> you know, the house that we lived in,
you know, the there was a guy living
there cooking meth in our house and then
there was caution tape around our house.
I mean, it was embarrassing. I mean, it
was bad and he was in a dark spot.
>> But here I make this phone call thanking
him and wanting to let him have it, but
I couldn't. He began telling me how
sorry he he was of how apologetically
how, you know, he'd been a really rough
year and all of that.
>> It began sinking in, you know, that that
I had hit rock bottom and and I and I
had
>> and and and it was humiliating. Uh I
wasn't I had to move out of my home. It
it was just that bad because the crowd
that was hanging around there all the
time
>> and I had I had uh
>> like Cindy said, "I told the guy that
that um
>> there was a guy reconstructing our my
home at that time doing reconstruction
and I'd heard that he might be cooking
meth in my home." And I asked him, I
said I said, "Are you're not I said I
heard that you were that you was cooking
meth in my home." He said, "Oh, no. We
were on the outside when that happened."
And and and the the the DOA, the drug
the drug course uh agency, they were out
in the tree line listening. I mean, this
sounds like something you
>> see on a movie.
>> Yeah, for sure.
>> They were listening. They were listening
to our conversation and it cleared me
>> because they thought that I was involved
in that. I never sold anything. I was
just
>> bought and did a bunch of them. But, uh
but anyway, they that cleared me and
they after I left, they raided my home
and got that guy He might still be in
prison today.
>> Wow. But at the court case, you know,
that I was asked to be there when they
were interviewing jurors for it. And all
these people, all all these people, I I
knew these people. I I did their tax
return. I I was their accountant or
their neighbor and and and it was so
humiliating. I mean, when I say I hit
rock bottom, I hit rock bottom because
it was a small community that my family
knew everybody in that community and it
was
>> it was a dark, humiliating time of my
life.
>> But God.
>> Yes. But God. So, I mean the So, all of
that was happening. I You had to step
out of the to separate, Cindy, because
it just wasn't a safe space for you.
>> It was a safe space. God protected me
and my two-year-old little boy and it
was the very best thing that needed to
happen. You can pray from a distance. So
that's just my little nugget there.
>> Um,
>> see that word right there, that word is
for somebody that's watching or going to
watch this right there. Get
>> it. And I have a word for somebody else
out there. Maybe you've got a loved one
uh or a friend that that that drugs has
or or some addiction has got a hold on
them. I want you to know it's not the
person. it. It's the drug. So, a lot of
times they do things that that's so
against their character and you go,
"What is going on here?" Well, just know
the devil is trying to destroy them and
you can pray from a distance for them.
And every time you pray, it gives God a
channel to work in
>> to rescue them.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> So, you know, here we are. He's doing
better. Actually, I'm still not with
him, but I've made that phone call and
we're talking. And we decided that maybe
we could get together for dinner, bring
the boys together, and just talk, maybe
start things slow. It was a a long shot,
a super long shot, but we both agreed.
>> Yeah.
>> And so we we got together, had dinner.
None of our family knew this was going
on. I mean, it's just it was just
between us. Our boys got together and
had dinner at my place. Um, you know, I
was back living about 30 miles from the
farm and um, it it it was going really
well. I mean, it was awkward. It was
great for the boys. It was a little
awkward, but we talked about a lot of
things. Well, southern Arkansas has a
lot of storms, and that night was no
exception. And there were tornado
warnings everywhere.
And I'm like, you guys can't leave right
now. You need to let the weather clear.
Well, it ended up being a allnight camp
out at my duplex.
>> And
>> so God sent a tornado.
>> God sent a tornado. Um the next morning,
they got up, went home, went on my life,
and I thought, well, okay, this might
mean something. We can, you know,
whatever. Well, almost six weeks later,
believe it or not, I'd heard zero from
him. Not a call, nothing. Silence.
>> And I was like, "Well, what what was
that?"
>> Well, I was at the operating room and I
was really busy that day and I bent down
to pick up something off the floor and I
got super super dizzy
>> and my girlfriend's like looking at me
and I'm like, "Oh, I just haven't had
anything to eat. I'm just tired." So, I
did what any other responsible young
woman would do and I clocked out and
went and got some Chinese fried rice and
went by the drugstore
and picked up a couple of pregnancy
tests.
And I went home and took a pregnancy
test and within seconds it was positive.
>> And those things are wrong sometimes.
So, chunk that one. Let's do another
one. And it was positive. Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
>> That's not what I
>> Oh man, I did not need that.
>> So God sent it sent a storm. You guys
took cover and then you don't hear from
him for six weeks, but there was
something cooking.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Baby baby Reese was cooking. So, um, we
I called him and, um,
got him on the phone. I'm I'm going over
a few details here, but he he answered
the phone or called me back rather. I
left a message and he said, "I I wow, I
can't believe you're pregnant." He said,
"This is just what I needed to make me
straighten up." And I thought,
>> "Okay."
>> And and he was all this going on, but
here's what he told me. words I'll never
forget.
And he said, I like some of the
crickets. Um, he said, "I promise you I
will make you the best husband you've
ever had. I will be there tomorrow to
pick you up and start moving you back
home."
And I told my girlfriend, I was at my
girlfriend's house when I got the when I
got the call back. And I looked at her
and told her and she just looked at me
and she goes, "M,
you're not going to fall for that, are
you?"
>> Well, let me interject here because
it's it's important, I think, for for
the those watching here to understand
that from the bottom of my heart, I
meant every word I said. That is just
what I needed. You see, and I hope
you're following this. Um, it's just
what I needed to straighten up again.
It's just what I needed. This is just
what I need. Now, now we This is just
what I need to be the the good husband.
Uh, the the the good even the Christian
that I need to be. Uh, it's it's it's
what I need to do. And I was here I was
again going to do it with 100% of my
strength. Everything I had, I was going
to try to be a good husband and a good
dad to that child. Yeah.
>> And I tried and and and really I guess
this would be a good place to kind of
move forward on this because I tried and
and and what would happen is I would be
really good for for for about a month
>> and it was almost like the pressure
building up
>> like a pressure cooker.
>> Yeah. And and and you could see the
pressure building up. I mean, I would
put all this effort into it, trying
really hard, you know, to be that that
good husband and and then and then I
would explode and and so I'd be really
good for a a while and then and then
boom, I'd be really bad. And this was
our cycle again.
>> And it was the addiction. It was the
addiction
>> addiction to me. And I was trying to do
it on my own strength. You see, I was
trying to to to be good on my own
strength.
>> Yep.
So, you know, there were good times, you
know, clearly um there were a lot of bad
and uh plenty of them and some of them
I've honestly pushed from my mind.
They're not even uh we wrote a book
right before COVID hit, actually. And um
we we couldn't put everything in the
book. I mean, you know, we had to keep
it G-rated for all audiences. Um but but
clearly uh there's enough there that
anyone can see that the devil was,
>> you know, trying to take us down, tried
to trying to destroy something we didn't
know. And I I want to share this with
you. Um on our very first blind date,
I'm a journaler, too. I am I can't
praise uh journaling enough. I couldn't
have wrote the book without the journal.
But
>> the very first night we went out, he
left and I got my journal out and I wish
I had it here with me to read exactly
what I wrote.
>> But it was basically at the very I don't
even know. It wasn't me writing it. It
was the Holy Spirit because I said,
"I've met the love of my life, the
person I want to spend the rest of my
life with, blah blah blah blah." And I
said, "Lord, if you can work this out
for us, I promise we will serve you the
rest of our life." Now,
>> wow.
>> Right.
>> We did. You weren't even in that mindset
before you.
>> God had a plan. He had a plan for
>> God had a plan for our life.
>> But what what he needed and this is so
important
>> because there's others that that God's
got a plan for someone in in your sphere
of influence. It might be a family
member. It might be a spouse. Yeah.
>> Could be a son or daughter.
>> But but in order for that plan to be
fulfilled, he needs someone to stand in
the gap. someone to intercede. Uh and
and that's what had God had a plan for
my life, but he needed someone to to
really get serious interceding on my
behalf
>> uh for for for that plan to be
fulfilled.
>> Absolutely.
>> In my life.
>> So, so I mean honestly I we talked about
God a lot on our first date because you
know, but as far as like anything, what
did that mean serve you? I have no clue.
That was God. truly gone.
>> We didn't know then. We know now.
>> Didn't know now. I mean, didn't know
then, but we know now.
>> So, oh my goodness, Aante. So, we're
back together and things are up, down,
up, roller coaster, like crazy.
>> Yeah.
>> And it got pretty intense. It matter of
fact, it it was building pretty heavy
around September 10th of uh 2001, the
night before,
>> you know, the attack on America. And
that night in our home felt like a 911
situation. This was the night before
911. We probably had Yes. We probably
had one of the worst intense
>> fights of our life.
>> Yeah. We probably need to call the
fireman to put out the fire in our
house.
>> Oh wow.
>> My goodness.
>> I normally don't I normally didn't
confront him. Um this particular night
he came in uh high. I didn't realize
what he'd been doing on came in like at
3:00 a.m.,
>> you know, flipping on lights. I had to
be at the operating room at, you know,
6:00 a.m. And I gave him a piece of my
mind that night. And and we just fought
all night. I ended up in the other
bedroom and whatever. And I woke up the
next morning. I'd called in sick. I I
woke up with a phone call saying, "Are
you guys watching TV? We just
>> there's been an attack." Right? And I
remember being so numb that day because
I was sad for America. I was sad for us.
And and I didn't see how we could ever
move past it. But
>> somehow we did. And then by 2003, it was
really explosive. I mean, it was just
getting insane how bad it was.
>> She was getting tired of it because it
was it was it was a I'd be good for a
while and then I'd be bad and it wasn't
getting any
>> and the bad was getting really bad. I
think she was was at the end of her
rope.
>> Yeah, I definitely
>> And rehab you never you never went into
rehab during this time. You always just
tried to face it. Wow.
>> Do it on my own. I was trying to do it
on my own.
>> Yep.
>> So, I made a plan, a getaway plan.
>> Okay.
>> And I was my mind was made up. I mean,
you know, a woman's mind, you can't
really change it, right? Right.
I was done. And so I had already made
plans to find a place to to move so I
could take, you know, my boys and get
out and never look back. This was it. It
wasn't going to I mean, I'd already by
this time we were we were seven years
into a marriage.
>> Everybody said over and over.
>> Well, my friends, my family, even
spiritual people, they said the same
thing over and over again. They said,
"Cindy, Rick will never what?
>> Change. No, he'll never change. He'll
never change.
>> No, they believed it.
>> I believed it. I was pretty sure God
believed it, too.
>> Somebody was asking in the chat, "Were
you guys Adventist then?" And I
>> Oh, no. No. No.
>> I never never even heard of an
Adventist.
>> I had um I actually just need to preface
here. Um I actually worked at a hospital
in um souththeast Arkansas, Pine Bluff.
I've got a follower on here today that
uh we were at the same church with.
>> Um
I worked with four Seventh Day
Adventist. It's not an Adventist
hospital, but for them and I had watched
them for 10 years. 10
>> years that I was not an Adventist that I
watched their mannerisms and everything.
>> So I had Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> So I I I had a plan to get away. Uh, I
was attending church at the alter now.
By now, I'm all into church. I mean, I'm
like, you know, I'm not as good as I
should be, but I'm I'm get I've gotten
better, better, better. And I'm in the
bathroom getting ready for work. Had
that plan to leave. But I cried out to
God
one last time. I gave it all I had early
in the morning. I said, 'Lord, I need a
miracle and I need it now. Yes, Sister
JRMC, that's right. I need a miracle
now. Now,
up to this time,
I can honestly say I'd never heard God
speak to me.
>> But that all changed that very morning.
And God was very clear. He was very
direct. He didn't mince his words. And
he said,
"If you leave your husband,
you will not have a testimony.
>> I want to use your husband in the
ministry." Oh my goodness.
What?
>> Are you sure, God? Do you know? I mean,
this is my redneck cut off sleeve
husband that drinks, does drugs, he's
the pornography. It You name it, it was
there.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'm like, "No way. No, no way." But
you know what? When God speaks, you
listen.
>> Amen.
>> And he still speaks.
>> He still speaks. So
>> deep breath for me.
>> So you So you heard that voice. Um
>> that stopped you from from leaving.
>> It did. It did.
>> Yeah. And what happened?
>> Tell Rick what? Did you ever tell Rick
what God said?
>> Not at that not at that time. No.
>> But listen. But listen what happened uh
as she I didn't know this had happened
but I knew something had happened to her
>> because she began she began uh going to
bed every night with the Bible in her
lap.
>> She began getting up every morning 4:00
in the morning with a Bible in her lap.
>> And and and and then her personality
changed. She changed the way she treated
me. Changed
>> her countenance. Changed
>> for the first time in my life. I
witnessed God really working in
someone's life. And I knew it had to be
God. And I'm going to give you an
example of something that happened. Um,
one of my friends uh that that worked
for me came on the farm uh came by about
3:00 one afternoon. We were Cindy was
preparing uh dinner for our family and
and u he we we decided we were going to
go out drinking. Well, we told her that
we were just going to go to the store,
you know, and then come back. Now, this
was 3:30 probably by that time,
something like that,
>> close to 4. And and we come back 12
hours later at 3:30 in the morning. And
uh so you understand and we we come in
the in in the house and we started
raiding the refrigerator for something
to eat. So we were making all kind of
noise. Well, Cindy gets up and starts
coming down the hallway and I just
looked at my friend and
>> with a baseball bat. Just kidding.
>> Yeah. No. And I knew remember she had
told you what happened before when I
come in late. Well, I knew what was
supposed to happen. It was expecting it.
It was supposed to be World War II. Uh,
and but you know what she did? She
walked up and she said, "Okay, guys."
She said, "What are you hungry for?"
>> She fixed us breakfast.
>> And now I still I still, you know, I
poisoned breakfast. I'm
>> You know, I I really hard. But I
>> That is That is God. That is the God in
your life right there. But go ahead. I
don't know what I don't know how many
women would do that.
>> That's right. And so I asked her, see, I
was up about 8 o'clock the next morning
because I had to go down the farm. And
because I I'd walked away from my CPA
firm, but I still had my farm and I
still had the responsibility with that.
And I and I always I never stopped doing
that. Anyway, um I asked Cindy, I said I
asked her, I said, "Why?" She said,
"Why? What?" I said, "Why were you so
nice to me last night?" And she said,
she said, she said that it wasn't me.
That was Jesus. Now, I want you to know,
>> amen.
>> That sermon, that sermon
>> touched my heart. That was a lifecher
for me because I knew that was God.
>> And from that moment on, something
started stirring in my heart. Something
started stirring in my heart.
>> Uh, and and I started asking her
questions.
>> Yeah. It it it's almost kind of it's not
comical about faith,
>> but I had this little sticker on the
refrigerator and it says faith comes by
hearing by hearing the word of God. And
I love your shirt. I got to get one of
those.
>> I he walked by and says, "What does that
mean?" Now,
>> and Pastor Ivor, I mean, you don't know
him in that life. You only know him as
Pastor Rick, you know, right? And to
it's it's like, what? What do you mean?
What does that mean? So, I explained to
him what I felt that scripture meant.
And he began asking all kinds of
questions. I was like, I don't know what
you're doing, God, but you are working.
You are doing something.
>> My mind and my heart started spinning.
And about that time, you know, Cindy had
mentioned earlier that she worked with
some Seventh Day Adventists. And um and
these these these guys were different.
They didn't they didn't tell the dirty
jokes. They didn't operate. They didn't
hit on the nurses. They didn't use the
foul language. And anyway, one of these
guys she had noticed and that he would
>> one in particular,
>> one in particular, his name was Dave. He
would do anesthesia dur for the surgery
and then he'd pull out his prayer
journal and prayer bookante
>> and he would start and he would start
going through this prayer book and and
Cindy asked him, she said, "Would you
mind putting my husband on your on your
book and pray for him?" And so someone,
this is so important, someone I didn't
know, someone just like you, someone
like watching here today that I didn't
know started praying for me,
>> praying for me. There's power in
intercessory prayer.
>> Yes. Amen.
>> So this guy was pray this Seventh Day
Adventist was praying for me
>> and and uh and he prayed for me about
probably about oh eight or nine months
probably. And we and I didn't know it,
but he was praying for me. So we had
Cindy where she worked at, they had a
>> like an operating room Christmas get
together party.
>> Operating room Christmas get together
where they would provide a really nice
meal and then and then and at a very
nice place and then and then afterwards
for those that wanted to stay uh they
had a usually a band or a DJ or
something and and have music and dance
and and they also would have a bar
there. And what I recommend, what I
>> That was a prote
I knew, of course, I knew how to mix
drinks and so I volunteered to run the
bar. So here I am this night.
>> Eagerly volunteered.
>> Yeah. This
>> this was BC before Christ for me. Uh I'm
I'm setting the bar up for for after the
meal. Well, I wasn't even eating. I was
just setting the bar up. this guy, the
Seventh Day Adventist Dave, who I didn't
know, who had been praying for me, came
walking up to where I was at
>> and I was watching it from a distance.
>> She's watching. And and so we talked for
probably 45 minutes while everybody else
was eating
>> and he didn't want any alcohol. He
didn't want anything to drink. And I
told my wife afterwards, I said, "It's
just something about that guy.
>> I can't put my finger on it, but it's
just something different about him." And
she said, "He's a Christian. He is a
Christian. And I told her, I said, "You
know what?" I said, "That guy was not
fake. He was real." Of course. Now, Ira,
I know now. Yeah.
>> What what it was about him. He was a
witness for Jesus Christ. He was
anointed with the Holy Spirit.
>> He prayed. He had prayed. He had the
anointing of the Holy Spirit going with
him for him and and in our in our
conversation.
>> And so, uh, so we're we're
time rocks on. She goes to work the next
Monday and and tells him, she said, "You
know what? You might be able you might
be able to reach my husband."
>> Yeah.
>> And and so he came down to my house. I
was at the farm and he came down to my
house. He tried more than once. It was
like a 30 35 minute drive down from
where he lived at to my home. And he
came down and he one day I he drove up
in the driveway and I recognized him as
soon as he got out of the car because
this guy was like 6'6 and uh a big tall
nice looking guy, sharp looking guy. Um
you know, an epsilon looking guy, you
know. But anyway, yeah, he he he gets
out of his car and and and I walk up to
him
>> and he said something to me that I'll
never forget.
>> He said he said, "Rick, the Lord has
laid you on my heart. Would you like to
study the Bible with me?"
>> Nobody had ever asked me to study the
Bible before. Nobody. I didn't look like
somebody that would want to study the
Bible. I didn't smell like it, talk like
it. I uh I didn't look like somebody
that would be interested, but I said
yes.
>> And simultaneously, you know, I'm
reaching out to God my own way now
because that that morning after that
that I heard God speak to me, I got up
the next morning at 4:00 a.m. and sat
down with my Bible and a devotional or
and and a journal and I said, "Here I
am, Lord. What are we going to do about
this?" Because I don't see any way out
of this. you said. So I started putting
it back, you know, in God's corner. I'm
like, you said it, so you know, and from
the very beginning, Ephesians 3:20
became an anthem verse for me. Um, I'm
just going to read it here. Now to him
who is able to do exceedingly,
abundantly, above all,
>> and I put that Cindy could ask or think
>> according to the power that works in.
So, I started um you know, taking these
scriptures and uh you know,
personalizing them, putting my name in
there and making them real to me. And
so, I'm praying these kind of things and
and I I I'll be honest with you. In the
beginning, here's how my prayers went.
Dear Lord,
>> my husband is a jerk. Please change him.
>> I'm just being honest. That's how I
felt.
>> Thank you. We appreciate it.
>> That's how I pray.
>> Okay. as I begin to draw nearer to God.
And another favorite was Jeremiah 33:3.
Call unto me and I will answer and show
you great and mighty things that you do
not know. All of these have just flooded
back to me now all these years later.
It's like God was doing something
amazing. But I realized that my prayers
were kind of making me kind of nauseous.
I'm like, okay, this is I need to
reorient here. And I was just overcome
with grief and sorrow and everything.
And I I dropped to my knees because I'd
been reading a book about forgiveness
and I realized that I had so many things
I needed to work through and forgive.
And that's not an overnight process.
>> But I dropped to my knees and I said a
very simple prayer because here's
another freebie. God's not interested in
our long elaborate prayer. You know
what? You know,
>> we don't have to do all that.
>> King James version.
>> We don't have to do all that. That's
right.
>> No fancy words. I'm just a country girl.
It's like, let's just keep this simple.
And so I dropped to my knees and I was
balling and I said, "Dear Lord,
give my husband a new wife
>> and let it be me."
>> And he did. He did. He honored that
prayer. And I'm going to tell you what,
when she forgave me, it there was a
change came over her. That's when her
countenance changed. That's when her
attitude, how she responded back. I was
still doing the same things, but she
responded differently.
>> Um, so we we started u that that that
night. Cindy, I didn't I didn't tell her
uh that Dave had come by.
>> I knew he had, but he he didn't know
that I knew. And vice versa. And so
we're in the bed that night and I'm just
it was one of a rare night that you
actually came to bed early and it we
were laying there in the darkness and
the silence of the night and I said
this all I said. I said, "So when are we
going to start doing those Bible
studies?" That's all I said.
>> I knew I mean I knew that David come and
offered it. He didn't know I knew.
That's all I said. And there was
silence. Just so much silence in the
darkness. and he said, "Let's start this
Thursday." Meaning, you know, I think
this is like whatever day that was,
Monday, Tuesday.
>> And I was like high-fiving God in the
dark.
>> Now, this this is what everybody has
been waiting on because this is where
God shows up in a powerful way because
we started we started studying the Bible
together on Thursday nights. And and and
this got Dave and then and then some
other uh other uh members from the Pine
Love Church would would come to my
house. They come to our house on
Thursday night. Yep.
>> And we would open up the word of God.
Now, I I had slacked off on on my drug
use,
>> but my drinking had increased.
>> I was using I was using alcohol as a as
as the filler for for the other. And so,
I drank every day. And the and these
guys would would come down to to and
come down the house and and open up the
word of God. And I'm telling you, the
very first thing that happened is I is I
filled my life with Jesus. Now, I want I
want to make a statement here. You you
cannot over overcome something that got
that has a hold on you by by working on
trying to overcome whatever it is that's
got a hold on you. Uh Hebrews 12:1 and 2
says, "Now it's time to set aside that
sin that so easily besets us." Now if if
that's all if that was the only verse,
we would have I'd be hopeless. But the
very next verse, verse two, says, "By
fixing our eyes upon Jesus, the author
and the finisher of our faith. What
happened to me?"
>> Now remember all these years, I had been
trying really hard to be that good
husband. I I'd put every effort I had to
it. I was failing miserably and so many
other people are failing. When we point
out people's uh problems or their or
their shortcomings, that's not going to
help them. We need to point them to
Jesus. And that's exactly what these
guys did. They pointed me
>> I just I love it because we just did we
just concluded a series a six week
series on spiritual and religious
trauma. And so
>> what what I see is like the the the
people that were studying the Bible with
you, they weren't judging you or they
didn't come and condemn you. They knew
you were drinking every day. I mean,
they could they could help that, right?
>> They knew that. Um and I'm just thinking
like when do we stop being like that and
then we once people join the church and
then they make like some mistakes or
doing something wrong or whatever, we
change into these other people. But I
don't want to interrupt your story
anymore, but it was just powerful that
they absolutely
>> how they were able to stay silent and
just
>> keep pointing you to Jesus and keep
study and keep moving.
>> All about Jesus.
>> Exactly. And Tante, I'm glad you brought
that up because that needed to be
highlighted because that's the only way
to help anybody is pointing them to
Jesus.
>> Well, any other way for you, you would
have probably said, "Hey, get out of my
house."
He would have been not nice, probably.
>> But I tell you what happened. Uh after
after God worked a miracle in our life
and everything, I was talking to one of
the guys and I said, "Did y'all not
smell alcohol in my breath?" And and he
said, he just looked at me, he started
laughing. He said, "A lot of times we'd
get in the car and said, "Man, if we lit
a match tonight, we'd all blew up." But
but they they never said a word about it
at Dante. They they just kept feeding me
Jesus, pointing me to Jesus. And so I I'
I've used a a phrase I've heard somebody
say one time. You cannot you cannot
stomp sin out of your life, but you can
crowd it out with Jesus. As I as I
>> Oh, yeah.
>> That's a t-shirt.
>> Yeah. As I filled my life with Jesus,
>> all the other stuff was spilled out. And
it didn't happen all at once. It was the
drugs first. The drugs was the first
thing to go. Uh the next thing to go was
lust. I had a terrible lust problem. It
it went with my lifestyle. Uh, and it
was just terrible, a terrible lust
addiction is what it was. And and um,
you know, I had a beautiful wife. Why
would I even need to look at at other
girls or look at X-rated material or
anything like that, but I did because I
was addicted because it had a hold on
me.
>> And and I remember as I filled my life
with Jesus, Yeah.
>> I was convicted by it. I
>> I I even thought it was normal for guys
to look at things like that because we
me and my buddies would just swap things
out, movies and stuff like that. And uh
but uh but I was powerfully convicted by
it. And I I remember I took I had a box
of really bad stuff, you know, x-rated
movies and things like that. And I went
out and I burned it.
>> I burned it. And I want you to know when
I did that, I was completely set free.
And I had I had been faithful to God and
faithful to Cindy ever since that that
when I burnt that
>> to her and and then so al drugs first
and then and then the lust and the next
thing had a grip on me was alcohol.
>> Now alcohol is something that that where
we grew up at any farmer most farmers
anyway have have a shop and in the shop
they have a refrigerator and in the
refrigerator they have beer. And so
that's a common thing for us just about
to as we visit with each other, we'd
socialize, we would we would we would
drink. And so drinking had been
something that was just been really
common in my life uh ever since I was
even a
>> probably 16 or 17 years old.
>> And and so I it had a hold on me. And so
I noticed I started noticing something
as I got to where in the mornings I'd
get up and I would I would spend time
with the Lord and and then I would go
out to the farm and start to work and I
would notice that that that that
alcohol had no grip on me at all until I
went out. But once I went out then it
then it would just pounce on me. You
know, somebody would drive up and offer
me a beer or whatever and then I would
start drinking again. And so what I
started doing is I started uh I'd go to
bed, you know, after drinking, you know,
quite a bit and I'd wake up at 2 or 3:00
in the morning and I'd roll out of bed
and I'd get on my knees
>> and I would pray a simple prayer.
>> Lord, I'm in a rut. Help me.
>> And that was it. I'm in a rut. So I
began to get convicted that that the
alcohol had a hold on me. And I remember
going the first day uh God convicted me
one day. I was looking out my kitchen
window and and he said, "Okay, this is
it. You don't need this anymore."
>> And and I said, "Okay, I'm not going." I
thought that I had to drink to go to
sleep. I thought it was my sleeping
pill, my to relax and and everything.
And so I remember I went all day long
>> and I did not drink a drop.
>> And and uh and and yeah, and I went to
bed and I fell asleep like a baby. And I
woke up at at like uh 2 or 3 o'clock in
the morning as usual. I got on my knees
and I it's just like I just got a big
fair hug from Jesus. I mean, I could
just sense his light and his presence
all around me. And and I started I
started quoting Psalms 119 verse 96
through 105. Oh, how sweet you are,
sweeter than honey. Your your your words
are a lamp into my feet, light into my
path. I just started just praying this
and praising it back to God. next
morning. That was a devotion that I that
that in my devotional books I knew it
was a message from God. I had been set
free and and they've been free ever
since. God set me free. Uh and I didn't
have to go to any rehabs. I didn't have
to go to to um I I and and you know
people, you know, you've heard when
people get anxious or irritable when
they go about, you know, I cigarettes
too. God give me free freedom over
tobacco also and and no rehabs, no
shakes, not anything.
>> And as a nurse, I was very concerned
about, you know, withdrawal issues.
>> The key to it was filling my life with
Jesus. And I had to get radical about
it. I had to I had to turn my my rock
and roll music off.
>> I had to I had to I had to open up the
word of God. Me choosing
>> choosing to fill my my life with Jesus.
And as I did that, God set me free.
>> And
>> wow.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> I mean, I I realize the pathway is
different for so many people. Some some
people and rehab needs to be the door
they need to go through, right?
>> It's different for everyone. You can't
look at someone and go, "Oh, this is the
way it's going to work."
>> God God has to guide and and direct.
>> He does. He does. I think about the
about the about the twins, T and Adam.
like
>> uh Adam got clean. It was very very hard
on his own. Him and God in an apartment
and it was it was really it was some
rough few days.
>> Uh but then his brother, his twin
brother who also had addiction, he had
to go to rehab and that's how he
>> got clean. So you know everybody you're
right, everybody's story is different
and that's what God did for you. Yeah,
>> Rick. And so yeah, that's what
>> So when did you go ahead?
>> That's what And then he, you know,
remember he put it on Cindy's heart that
he was going to use us in the ministry.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, it's incredible what happened
then. He didn't stop then. Not only did
he set us free, but he but he set us on
fire. Matter of fact, we have we have
people all at first would tell us that,
"Oh, don't to get your host built up.
He's probably gonna he's gonna he's
going to lose that fire after a while."
Wow. Let me tell you what, at one time
we needed we needed the firemen to come
to set the fire out because it was so
crazy. But now but now we're on fire for
Jesus.
>> Amen.
>> And so what happened Ivor and Atante is
that uh God worked really fast in our
life. We were baptized
>> uh in into the in in 2004, baptized into
the Seventh Day Adventist Church. And uh
again, I had never heard of a Seventh
Day Adventist before they started
studying the Bible with me.
>> And u but anyway, we were baptized and
within a year uh within a year I was
asked to be an elder at the church and I
we started sharing our testimonies. We
we were asked to share our testimony 380
yen and uh and and and and then we would
just go to different churches sharing
our testimony. And then and then um we
felt God calling us in the ministry. We
just sensed, you know, we just we just
we just sensed him calling us.
>> Cindy already knew.
>> Yeah. And she knew.
>> Yeah. She already knew. But but God uh
but but God was really tugging at her
heart to do this. And so we made up our
mind that we were going to give the rest
of her life to God. We made a decision.
We made a decision. It's all about
choices. And we made a decision that we
were going to give the rest of our life
to God. Whatever he wanted us to do,
wherever he wanted us to go, whatever.
>> Remember, I wrote that in the journal
the first night.
>> That that that is true.
>> Yes. The journal.
>> Yes.
>> But we made that decision to do that.
And I remember my mom and and somebody
on the on the on the the feed here knows
my mom. um she come up to us and we were
telling our telling my mother that we
were going to um give the rest of our
life to God in ministry and my mother
made a comment
>> and she said if God wants you in the
ministry he'll provide somebody to buy
your farm
>> that night that night without without
advertising
>> this this commercial poultry farm that
night somebody called and wanted to buy
our farm
>> it wasn't
it wasn't listed for
>> let me tell you about my Jesus
>> that is God
>> right and so what we did we what we did
we recognized this was God and we went
to the lawyer's office and when we went
to the lawyer's office and then we
signed on on a dotted line a contract a
lease with an option of purchase
>> uh is what we did we did that because
the the the young man didn't have the
collateral to to borrow that kind of
money so it's right kind of like a
stellar finance but it was a little bit
of legal different legal uh avenue to
avoid income taxes. But anyway, we went
that route. But when I walked out,
>> when I walked out, when we walked out of
that lawyer's office, for the first
time, my security was not in my income
making ability. My whole adult life, my
in I did I did well, you know, with
income making, but now we still owed on
the farm. And we every penny every penny
that we were going to be making we were
going to make back to our note payment
on the farm which meant my my income my
security was not my income. It was
totally in God.
>> And we had to rely completely on Cindy's
uh income that she made from nursing.
And so and she was fine with that. That
says a lot for my wife by the way. Not
only she she pray for me but she was
willing to let me just just serve God
for free. That's what I was going to do.
I I was just going to I was going to
serve the Lord any way he wanted me to
to use me. I never thought I'd go into
pastoral ministry.
>> Um but we we began serving God for and
and I asked the pastor, "What can I do?"
And he and and he said, "Well, you can
go visit." So I had a F250
Ford diesel truck
>> and I would drive that thing. I'd put
200 300 miles a day on that vehicle to
visit people.
>> Wow. It was a I can't even imagine
diesel so high now, but it was a
guzzler.
>> It was amazing.
>> So, we did that for for three months.
For three months and seemed like and
then and then it seemed like forever.
Everybody thought we had went crazy. All
our friends
>> uh thought, you know, oh, you're
carrying this religious stuff way too
far. Went off the deep end.
>> They should have they should have known.
They should have known to be like, you
know what, we think they're crazy, but
we we've seen God do too much. like they
should have known but they were so
doubting.
>> They were skeptical.
>> That's where they were at a time. They
just thought they didn't have faith in
our big God, right? No.
>> But anyway, three months later, I'm at a
food bank helping box up food for the
poor
>> and and I get a telephone call from the
president of the Arkansas, Louisiana
conference. His name is Steve Orian.
>> And uh man of God, man of God. Yeah.
>> And he said, "Rick, I hear you're on
fire for Jesus.
>> Would you be interested in pastoring two
churches in southern Arkansas?"
>> That's God. That's God. Amen.
>> Oh, that's God. In my ears, Atante, the
song, Great is Thy Faithfulness. Great
is thy faithful. It was angels singing
that song.
>> Wow. And and uh and I knew that that was
God opening up the door. He he did open
up that door. We pastored uh two
churches, Elora, Arkansas and Magnolia,
Arkansas. And we did that for two years.
God really blessed our ministry there.
>> Uh and then we were called to um uh to
the Oklahoma. That's where we met you
guys for the first time. Cindy was a
prayer coordinator and I was a pastor
out there.
>> And we we get out there and I want to
say this, this is just another
confirmation of God's faithfulness. We
get out to to Oklahoma and I'd just been
there a little while and I I had a
doctor in in my
>> in the church uh that that that and I
told him I said if you need a chaplain I
said let me know and uh and I'll come
visit you any way I can help out. Well,
he we just got out there and he he he I
he called me and he said, "I got
somebody that that's really just scared
of just really scared and they're
panicking thinking they're going to die
and they weren't even in intensive
care." And he said, "Could you could you
um could you visit this person?" And so
I did and and I I visited the person and
I and she was just a nervous wreck and
and about what she thought she was going
to die and and and so I just walked her
through the steps of giving her life to
Jesus
>> and and she gave her life to the Lord
and just like a total peace come upon
her. I left and I come back the next day
to visit her and the room was empty and
I I asked the the the nursing station
right across the room and I said, "What
happened to Miss Soandso?" She had died
right after I left.
>> Wow.
>> And but I had but Wow. But God had
confirmed that he prayed her asleep.
>> Yeah.
>> He used me to lead her to the Lord in
her life. So here I am. I'm just I'm
just overwhelmed at what God was doing
in my life. And I
>> He was using you.
>> Yeah. I get a telephone call from uh my
elder at my church and his dad was his
dad was u was he said, "My dad is in the
hospital. He's got a brain aneurysm and
he's not going to make it."
>> And and I said, "Oh, hi." And he said,
"I just called to let you so you could
pray with me." And I prayed with him. I
said, "Where's he at?"
>> And he was he was in Amarilla, Texas.
Now, Amarilla, we lived halfway between
Amarillo and and Oklahoma City. So, uh,
if you want to go anywhere where we
lived at, there was the two big towns.
And I and I head to Amarilla.
And I drive up to where the hospital's
at. And I walk in the hospital and God
stops me and and he says, "Look where
you're at." Now, what I'm about, this is
going to this is going to be a
tearjerker what I'm about to tell you,
but
God stopped me and said, "Look where
you're at." I was in the very same
hospital. the young man Dave that I
shared with you that had came and asked
me if I'd like to study the Bible had
been praying for me. Two weeks after our
baptism, Dave and his wife were on their
and family were on their way to Colorado
where her family lived at and they hit
black ice
>> and they lost control of their vehicle
and they were t-boned by 18 Willard and
and and and Dave's wife was killed
instantly and and he was medlighted to
Amarilla, Texas
>> to a trauma unit. Wow.
>> Okay. And there he died.
>> He didn't survive.
>> Yeah. He didn't survive.
>> Two weeks after our baptism. He has no
idea what type of real close.
>> Oh, wait. Heaven's going to be so sweet.
>> Yes, it is. Four years later, to the to
the to the very month, four years, four
only four years later, I'm in the very
same hospital. When I when this happened
to Dave, it was a 12-hour ride from
where I lived at to where to where Dave
was at. So, I didn't even go out to
Amarillo to see the guy that saved my
life.
>> It was just too far.
>> But now, four years later to the month,
God has me in that very same hospital
ministering to a family about to lose
their loved one.
>> Yeah. And it was a confirmation from God
>> that that that he had that I was right
where he wanted me to be at and right
where he wanted me to be doing. He had
called me in the ministry and he was
confirming it.
>> And and Ivor and everyone watching now.
>> I I have given my life to God every
single day since that moment.
>> Amen.
>> Every day I wake up, Cindy and I have a
prayer before we ever get up. We pray
when we go to bed, but before we get up,
we did this morning. We prayed for God's
leading and guiding and for his will to
be done in our life.
>> I know it's no accident that that we are
on this line right here today. And I
know it's no accident that we have
people watching.
>> Yes.
>> That's listening to what's going on
here. God has a message for you.
>> Uh Amen. That he loves you. He cares
about you. And he has a plan for
somebody's life that you know, and he
wants to work a miracle in their life.
But he needs you to stand in the gap and
pray for them. Yeah. Amen. So he could
work a miracle in their life.
>> Amen.
>> I got and I got one thing and I want to
shut up after that because I've been
doing a lot of talking.
>> You had to cut him off.
>> You made the statement. Heaven's going
to be so sweet.
>> It's gonna be so sweetant. I cannot
wait.
>> When I get to heaven, I'm running up to
Jesus
>> and I'm giving him a big hug for his
grace and his mercy and his love and
compassion in my life.
>> But after I get through hugging him, I'm
going for Dave and Amen.
>> I'm running for Dave. I'm running for
him.
>> And I can't wait to see
>> that God rescued me. God God worked a
miracle my life because of him. Because
because he prayed for me and he and he
opened up the Bible to me. He shared the
word of God. He shared Jesus to me.
>> And and behind me though,
>> behind meante is going to be all those
that I led to the Lord.
>> Amen.
>> See, it's not only going to be me. He's
going to understand why.
>> God is so good.
>> God is so so good.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. You know, it's not a mistake that
you guys are here today. This is a God
thing. I know like I reached out to
Cindy earlier or this week, but it's
still last minute and this just happened
to be a Sabbath where you guys were both
available because I know your schedules
are so busy. And so that that's just
God. And so it was a blessing to us.
Like thank you for for telling us the
story again because you you refreshed
our memory of all what God has done. And
>> there is somebody who's on here live
right now that this was for and there's
going to be thousands of replays after
we're done. Absolutely.
>> And it is for somebody it is for so many
to hear. And it is our prayer that
>> there's someone I talked to this two
days ago.
>> Okay.
>> That this was specifically for.
>> Amen. And I hope that person is
watching.
>> Amen.
>> Praise God.
>> Amen. Amen. Amen. We we want to let
people know um how they can get a hold
of your book because they want to hear
all the details that they miss um and
just to you know be able and to follow
your ministry as well. So I believe uh
we have a slide for that or we have the
information. I think that's going to go
up in the chat or it's going to go on
the screen. Um I believe our our tech
team has that. So, uh, while they're
pulling that up, we just want to say
thank you. Thank you. Thank you
>> for your faithfulness. And it's amazing
because we have kind of lost contact
over the years. I mean, we see each
other on social med.
>> I know we can't we have to reconnect. I
we I follow you on social media, so I
see all the things that are going on,
but we don't actually like talk talk.
And so, just knowing how much God has
even done since we have blasted you guys
is just amazing. And we just praise God
for that. I mean, your ministerial
director, Rick, I mean, I remember when
we met you.
>> Amazing.
>> Yeah. Like,
>> amazing.
>> It's It's all God though. I mean, it's
100% because we have a we have a friend
and and she'll say something to somebody
and she says, you know, that that that's
that's good, Rick. That's real real
good, Rick, but you're not that good.
It's all God doing it. So, you know, she
has to share something. So,
>> great is his faithfulness. And you know
what? The best is yet to come.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> The best is yet to come. When we look
what God has done for us in the past,
>> think about this. Heaven is going to be
so good.
>> Heaven is real. And and think about what
God went through just that we could be
there with him. I mean, yeah,
>> the best really is yet to come.
>> It's going to be beyond what we could
ever think or imagine. Good.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> There's there's so much we we wanted to
share, but can't. I know timing is
always an issue,
>> but um I just encourage people to uh I
tell people are like, you know what,
just don't try to look at the whole big
picture. You know, God impressed me to
pray and fast. And that's what I did. I
did not have a clue what I was doing,
but I did my very best and God honored
that.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I know I've said this several
times, but I think probably the most
important message here is that God had a
plan for my life.
>> But in order for that plan to be
fulfilled and carried out, he needed
someone just like you. Someone someone
just like you watching to start standing
in the gap and praying for me,
>> interceding and showing me Jesus. So, I
think it'd be just good if everybody
could just pray that prayer. Lord, I
give you permission to use me in the
harvest.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen. Amen.
>> Praise God.
>> Yes. We are uh working on getting that
information.
>> That's what the sermon is about.
>> Yes. Because we want people to be able
to get that get your book and be able to
read that. I know people want to and
they want to follow your ministry. And
so, um it's going to go in the chat and
if not, we'll have it up by the divine
worship so that they can get all that.
But you can even say what your website
is so some may catch it now.
>> Yeah. Super simple. It's just
www.mmercer
ministries. So that's m ceer m i n i s t
r i s. Mercer ministries.com.
>> Okay. And the name of the book the name
of the book
>> pray pray big.
>> Pray big. And they and they can get that
on they can get that on Amazon.
>> Amazon Kindle Nook.
>> Local ABC.
>> It's actually an audio. It just came out
audio a few months ago. So
>> Oh, that's cool. And it's and it's your
voice. Is it your voice that are you
guys? Are you guys reading?
>> Unfortunately, it's not. I
>> want to hear those accents.
>> I I wish I would have. Anyway, long
story, but it is not unfortunately. So,
>> Okay.
>> Well, I I I also think our prayer team
would love to have you guys one
Wednesday night.
>> Yes. Because we have two Wednesday
nights, whatever.
>> You guys like you will vibe with our
prayer team. I can tell you would be
very happy. We have an amazing Yeah, we
have amazing prayer leader, prayer team,
and they they they are absolutely
amazing. But you guys fit right into
that. So, I know they would want you to
um and it's in the chat, too. So,
someone may be reaching out to you for
that as well. Um but
>> I just want to say thank you, thank you,
thank you. Um it's been a blessing just
to hear your story again and just to
increase our faith like just to forward
all issues to heaven. I mean,
>> God had you, Rick and Cindy. Like, even
when you didn't even know how well I
mean,
>> that's right.
>> How to pray for that. He just He had
you. He had you and he had a plan. And
>> praise God. And you are living his will
and his plan out right now. So, we just
>> from the living man at church, we're so
thankful for what you have shared today
and what he's
>> We've got a new church family, too.
>> You do. whenever you guys can tune in
and when you can't, you can always watch
it after. So,
>> absolutely
>> be a part. We want you to be a part of
our
>> and we'll need to have you come preach
for us, too.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
>> Definitely.
>> Can I pray for everyone?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We were going to pray for you, but
yes, please pray for us.
>> Okay. All right. Father in heaven, we
believe in divine appointments, and we
believe that this has been a divine
appointment today. Uh when we look at
the time that we live in and we and we
and we study the prophecies in the
Bible, we know that you're coming soon.
We know that any moment that you could
be just busting through that eastern
sky. And so there's people in our lives
that that you want to reach. The harvest
is great, but the labors are few. So
dear God, would you please use each
person that's watching? Anoint them with
the Holy Spirit just like you anointed
day with the Holy Spirit. and use them
Lord to reach somebody for you, for the
kingdom, for your glory, Lord. In Jesus
Christ's name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Thank you so much, guys. Go
get the book. Pray big. Go find that and
bless yourself with the with the rest of
the story or the whole story. Um, but
yes, you will be hearing from us soon.
But thank you so much.
>> God bless you guys.
>> Thank you all for letting us love you
guys.
>> All right. Okay. God bless you.
>> Bye. Bye. Bye. Bye.
[Music]
Deep on the plains of this African
savannah, you find some of the most
remarkable people in the world. The
Messiah people of Kenya and Tanzania
live in one of the harshest environments
on the earth. There are so many things
that can kill you out here. Wild
weather, poisonous insects, ferocious
beasts, just to name a few. These
nomadic people live on the plains where
lions and cheetahs, leopards and
buffaloos and elephants roam freely.
They are shepherds and warriors, ever on
the lookout to protect their families
and their flocks. The Messiah warriors
are some of the bravest people on earth.
Many of them armed with only swords and
spears have slayed lions and hyenas in
order to protect their families and
their flocks from attack. These shepherd
warriors never leave home without their
shuka and their sword and spear. These
are the weapons they use against the
lions that may come their way. If a lion
approaches, the Messiah warrior will
take his shuka and wrap it around his
left hand. As the lion leaps, the
warrior gives his hand to the lion's
mouth. For a bitten hand is better than
a bitten head. But the shuka neutralizes
the bite. And as the lion is occupied
with the warrior's left hand, he is then
taken down with the Messiah sword or
spear in the right hand. As they face
the lion, the Messiah warrior shows no
fear. This is what makes them some of
the bravest warriors in the world.
I found it very interesting that the
Shuka colors are normally red with
trimmings of blue, sometimes purple. In
the Bible, a covering is a symbol of
righteousness. Red, which is the color
of blood, represents mercy and
sacrifice. Blue, the color of the law,
represents justice and righteousness.
And then when you blend red and blue
together, you get the royal color of
purple. So every day that the Messiah
warrior faces the dangers on the mara,
they are covered with the mercy,
sacrifice, righteousness, and justice of
the Lord. These are the attributes that
make them a part of the royal family of
heaven. The red, blue, and purple shuka
can easily be seen from miles away
across the brown backdrop of the African
savannah. Over the centuries, it seems
that the lions have been imprinted with
an innate fear whenever they see the
bright shuka of the Messiah warrior. The
Messiah Shuka also serves as a source of
warmth by night, shade by day, and a
place to sit and rest in their journey.
This special covering is the peculiar
mark of the Messiah, also serving as
their passport when traveling between
Kenya and Tanzania.
[Music]
As I spent time with these amazing
people and learned of the importance of
this beautiful African covering, it
shouted to me of the beautiful plan of
salvation. For just like the Messiah,
Jesus, the son of God, came to this
world as a shepherd. He came to rescue
his flock from the ravenous lion that is
seeking to devour us with deception. He
came to lead us beside green pastures of
grace and the still waters of love. But
he also came as a warrior covered in a
shook of mercy and justice. He came with
the sword of the spirit which is the
word of God to slay the satanic lion
with an it is written he conquered the
temptor's bite. He is the great warrior
shepherd that shows us how to fight the
battles of the Lord. But then at
Calvar's cross, he was stripped of
Yeshuka, and he received a mortal wound
from the lion's bite. He was stripped of
Yeshuka that we might be clothed in the
righteous covering of God. This is our
passport to heaven. For through his
death, we have the guarantee of life
ever more. For soon and very soon, this
warrior king will return in the clouds
of heaven, clothed in a shuka dipped in
blood, with eyes of fire, a crown on his
head, a sword in his mouth. He's coming
to slay the lion once and for all. And
just as a shepherd gathers his flock,
the heavenly warrior shepherd will
gather his people and bring them to the
evergreen pastures above.
My friend, you may not be a Messiah
warrior, but God calls you to be a
spiritual warrior for him. Remember that
the weapons of this spiritual warfare
are not carnal. For we do not wrestle
against flesh and blood. God's kingdom
is not of this world. In this spiritual
battle, we must fight the good fight of
faith with the sword of truth and the
shook of righteousness. And as we do,
God promises that we shall tread down
the lion and the serpent under our feet.
Satan's bite will have no power over us.
For Jesus, who is the ultimate warrior,
will lead us to final victory at last.
We cannot lose when Jesus we choose. So
choose him as your warrior shepherd and
allow him to cover you with his
righteous shuka today.
[Music]
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Hey.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
and welcome back to living matter
church. We have entered the divine
worship service. And can I tell you,
watching that replay of Rick and Cindy
Mercer, I was once again distraught by
the awesome
power in an individual's life. And if
God can do it for Rick and Cindy's
mercies for him personally and for their
marriage, he can do it for any one of
us. And I know all of us that are
watching live right now can ha we have a
story that we can share. And so please
know and be encouraged that wow God is
still doing miracles and no one nobody
across the face of this planet is exempt
from that transformative power. That's
how much God loves us. So despite
ourselves, he loves us even more than we
don't like ourselves because he knows
that if I get if they let me in their
heart, I can do wondrous things in their
life and their marriage, their testimony
is a living testimony to that. Same
thing can be said for Pastor Myers and
same can be said for me. Same can be
said for you. And so, um, we are just in
awe of God and we just want to give God
just the glory for making lives brand
new. Um, so once again, I want to thank
you for being here at Living Matter
Church. I am Patrice Lisser. For those
of you who do not know, I'm the
secretary here for Living Matter Church
as part also part of the tech team. Um,
as usual, per usual, I want to give a
good shout out to uh the ones holding me
down in the back today. Gavin, Anthony,
and Joshua Myers is back there holding
me down here today, making sure that I
can connect with you. And so, giving
Pastor Myers and Sister Atante a time of
celebration for the anniversary.
Marriage is absolutely beautiful. And
aren't they a great couple? And I'm not
just saying that because, you know,
they're friends family, but they really
are a great couple. So, if you wouldn't
mind just sending some love to them in
the chat. Happy anniversary. Let them
get the much much needed rest and
reconnection uh with God and with one
another. And um shout out. Now, I don't
know how long they've been married, but
I can easily say it's it's it's getting
up to a certain number. I'm not going to
say it. They'll say it themselves. But
anyway, everybody, happy Sabbath to you.
Big shout out once again to Power of the
Land Watchers. You're on here. But also
want to give a big shout out to our
Living Mana Church family. Listen, you
guys have been getting getting the
virtual memo. You have been bumping up
the numbers of our subscribers here
today and we have at today just a few
moments before I came back on here live,
we are hitting that 7,000 subscribers.
Give a shout out to yourselves. But
also, I told you we're going for seven.
You know, seven is like that perfect
number. Anything past that is just grace
and just new beginnings. You know, we're
we're we're about that life. But we're
at 6.61k
followers. So, thank you guys so much.
You have been a part of making sure that
our channel grows. You've been sharing
the links, sharing this uh the messages
throughout the week. You've been sharing
uh the different uh programs we've been
having during the week. And it's all of
you. You are Living Man Church. It's not
us in the back yet. You are Living Man
Church. and we are so thankful to serve
with you, come alongside with you, pray
with you, cry with you, grieve with you,
and rejoice with you. So, we really are
pleased to be here today. So, we've got
some announcements. As you know, Sister
Ati says all the time, and I'm saying it
to you. We are an active organism. I
We're more active. I'm going to say that
and really put my name on this right
now. I generally don't do that, but
today I am. We're more active than some
churches that have four walls. I'm just
gonna say it. We are a church without
walls that has so many different
auxiliaries and programs to connect with
one another and to be together and
different ministries and team leaders
and all the things we really this church
is on and popping. Can I just say that
we're on and popping? Can I say that? I
I did. Did I date myself? I probably
did, but it's okay. Um, but I do want to
um ask if you are a firsttime watcher
here and worshiper with us today, please
make sure you put that one in the chat.
Um, we have an amazing global family
that is always so excited to welcome
you. They call it your name, your
handle, and they really show you that
virtual love and sincere heart welcoming
every time they see that one in the
chat. So, if it's your first time
watching, please put them on the chat.
And I'm going to do a quick thing here
for just for just for like a 30 seconds
or so, 45 seconds tops. Where are you
watching from? What city? And in
particularly, what country are you
watching from? Some people say there's
a, you know, Texas is their own country,
but Oh, I didn't say that, but I did.
Anyway, um, please, what country you
watching from? We want to make sure we
give you that here. Uh, sister, yes, I
did, sis. I did say on and pop and I
did. Um,
so put in where you're watching from,
what country, what city you're watching
from, and let me see where I can see
everybody at here. I'm going through the
comments just to see. Uh, do I see
anybody here? Uh, let's go. Let's go.
Give me a city. Give me a state. I'm
looking for you to give a quick shout
out. You've got 10 seconds to do that.
And after that, we're going to keep it
moving. So, in the meantime, let's go.
Let's go. All right. So let's go to how
we stay connected to this living
organism called living mana church.
Let's go.
Our first way to connect is our text
messaging system. You all know that we
get real time on time action alerts as
to the programming. You got a
notification today inviting you to
church but also inviting you to also
share uh the link with other people
about the church. So, I'm copying the
links from our um YouTube channel to
invite people to come and worship with
us. And so, we get real time checks
alerts here um on your phone and
devices. And if you want to be a part of
our um automated announcement system,
please make sure if you in the
contiguous United States, you text LMOC
to 8552074107.
And that is a great way for you to
connect with us here. But if you're not
in the United States, we have a platform
called Mighty Networks. And Mighty
Networks is where our global family gets
together and we connect there on that
platform. And so we have a prayer wall
there. Uh people put songs on there and
scriptures on there. That is where we
have our afterglow. Um, generally every
single Sabbath after divine service, we
everything is that's the hub right now.
That really is the hub of how we connect
as a global family. So, please make sure
you sign up for Mighty Networks. Even if
you're in the United States, obviously
sign up for Mighty Networks as well, but
particularly to my international
viewers, please make sure you connect
with us there. And please invite a
friend, a co-orker, family member, it
doesn't matter. We want to just extend
the family. And once again, that makes
you a digital disciple.
Okay. So, now we're going to talk about
LMOC kids. They have already had their
worship service. That is such a blessing
for our young people. I get I hear
wonderful testimonies of how the
children are so excited about what God
is doing in their lives and the parents
are so just elated and caregivers to be
able to have that time where the kids
have their own service and they're
getting the the knowledge and the
experience of what it means to grow up
in the full knowledge and love of
Christ. And so shout out to everyone
that's part of that department making
sure that our young people are taken
care of. Uh we also have a teens
program, but this is not that. But I
just want you let we know we do have
that as well. So if you want more
information about that, um I'll make
sure uh we maybe do an email blast on
that as well. If you haven't joined our
email team, I'll let you know how to do
that at another time. But in the
meantime, LMOC Kids is active and
functioning. And if you if your child is
not a part of it, you can do it two
ways. First, you can do it through text.
Text KIDS kids to 855207-4107.
Or you'll see the email right there at
the bottom of that graphic. It says
lmocids
at living mana.urch.
Please share the mana with your
children.
Okay, we talked about subscribing. We
were already and I just made mention of
that because I wanted to get a jump on
that and just say, "Hey guys, there we
are. We are at 6.1 uh 61,000 followers
and no 6,6100
followers." So, please
make sure you subscribe to everything at
LivingMano on Instagram, on Facebook, on
Twitter. Um, please make sure you
connect with us there and also invite a
friend. Once again, when you do this, it
also jumps up the algorithm and makes
ensure that other people who like
content like this, they get a chance to
view it as well. So once again, every
time you share, um, you click like and
you subscribe, you are letting the
algorithm know, you're letting YouTube
know, hey, this is truly a wonderful
program, a wonderful ministry that other
people need to connect with. So, thank
you so much for all that you do to get
the word out about Living Matter Church.
We truly here appreciate it. We
absolutely do. Um, go. Today is your
day.
This is not just go as in go. This is
today you get to go out outside beyond
the walls. For those who can because I
do know we understand there are those
who cannot but there those of you who
can this is your day. There will not be
an afterglow today. Oh I know. I'm sorry
but pastor my sister Tatia way. And so
today is your day to go and just be a
minister be a disciple. Go share. We're
really excited about the opportunity for
you to get out there and let others know
about what's happening at Living Manor
Church. So, this is your opportunity
right now. When I when I say to you that
we were active inside, the whole premise
is to make you active outside the
church, outside the virtual walls, and
make you a disciple, not just digitally,
but also tangibly, but in service, in
community act, act acts of love. Please
make sure you're there. And so once
again, today is the go day. And here is
the motto. Let's go be the light. Let's
go be the church. Let's go make it
count. So today, let's go out there and
show Christ to others.
Communion service is coming up October
the 31st. So please mark your calendars
for that virtual communion service. And
for those of you who are wondering how
are you doing communion where we're not
in person, I promise you it is a
beautiful and rich experience. Uh you'll
get information as to how you can
actually make your own uh bread to be
able to serve one another, your family.
Uh maybe going to visit someone in the
hospital that can't, you know, take
communion. But you could also prepare
the sacraments of of of the communion
service itself at home and be prepared
to share it with others if you're by
yourself. So you'll get information on
and that recipe to make it as well as
the juice that's that is uh that you
need to get is 100% grape juice, not
alcohol, 100% pure grape juice as part
of the service for communion. Also, I
want to say if you have uh if you're
able to do foot washing because I know
some of you, many of you are probably by
yourself, um I would encourage you to
connect with another believer. Invite
them over. What a great opportunity to
invite them to church in your home. Open
your doors and you can have foot washing
uh with one another. Husbands and wives,
I would encourage you, listen to me. I
encourage you with all my heart. This is
a beautiful way for husbands and wives
to wash one another's feet before this
as well. So, um we'll be sharing more
about that as um how to make that even
extra special before uh Pastor Myers
leads out in the service of communion
virtually. So, uh please once again mark
your calendars, prepare your hearts even
now for that time. October the 31st at
700 p.m. Central Standard Time will be
communion. So, it's going to be on
Mighty Networks. And you do not want to
miss this blessing. I am not going to
miss this blessing. So, I will invite
you to come and join me as well. Looking
forward to experience the beauty of that
um just sacred service with you guys. I
really am. I really am. All right.
Hangouts. Hangouts is happening.
It is all under already underway.
Hangouts is taking place on the mighty
networks platform and you'll see all the
information here on the screen on the
graphic. But for those of you who need
to just hear me say it verbally, here we
go. The next hangout you're invited to
is Sunday, September the 7th on June.
Wait, can you believe that's going to be
next week? Like really, it's going to be
next week. Where is the summer? The
summer is flying by. So, Hangouts is
happening Sunday, September the 7th on
Zoom. Um, you for those of you who are
on your laptop, just grab your phone and
scan that QR code. Um, and you'll
connect with the Hangouts as well. Um,
if you want to if you'd like to be want
to host or host a hangout, that's really
cool. That's a great way for you guys to
say, you know what, I'm not part of a
ministry, but I'd love to be able to
host one. Well, it's like bringing
somebody into your virtual home. Make
sure you uh send an email to hangouts h
g o ts hangouts at livinga.urch and
that's taking place at 6:30 p.m. Central
Standard Time. And so it's going to be
fun games, ice breakers, just a lot of
just a lot a lot of just connecting with
one another. So I'm excited about
hangouts. I may be there, too. I think I
I'm gonna pop in the room as well. All
right, so here we go. our zoom
zoom we are moving we are moving we are
moving um we have a zoom has some things
that's happening on zoom I don't have
that information right now ah um that's
going to be taking place on the 1st of
September so we have programs that will
be taking place on zoom and you'll get
more information about that because I
have a couple of uh uh pieces of
information I want to share there. So
look for programs that will not be on my
networks but uh will be happening on the
Zoom platform. So let's go ahead and get
moving into that uh that first one which
is our star
initiative.
There we go.
We are
a church that cares about the whole
human experience.
And the STAR program
is really geared towards those who have
addictions, past addictions, or
currently need some support. Uh we are
here for you every Sunday, 11 a.m.
Central Standard Time. Uh this is our
addiction recovery program let out by uh
Gina and Ross Brower. Um, so definitely
if you if you or a loved one or someone
you like to invite just to be a part of
that to give support as in your journey
and your walk to sobriety to wholeness
in Christ through through the Christ
method alone, please make sure you send
a text to star s to that same number 855
uh 407.
I just saw it just now. I'm sorry. I
just saw it. and just and just send a
text message there to that number once
again and you're going to um connect
with us for that addictions program. Um
I'm sorry for some reason on my side my
card will not show. I'm not sure why,
but yes, uh please make sure if you sign
up for the text message alerts, that is
the same number that you will send the
text to S and you will get the
information for that. So once again,
you'll text it to that same number to
and you'll put in the letters S T AR.
Thank you guys so much. Our adult
Sabbath school will be taking place. It
takes place every single Friday, 6:30
p.m. Every Friday, the gyms is leading
out and contact Sister Tina Whitehead.
They are doing an active work. And for
those of you who'd like to do the adult
Sabbath school lesson, they do it every
single Friday. So you guys make sure you
be a part of that. uh join the uh Jim's
team as we dive deep into the Sabbath
school quarterly, unpacking scripture,
sharing insights, and growing together
in truth and grace. It happens at 6:30
p.m. Central Standard Time on Zoom. Uh
this isn't just a study. It's a space to
reflect, connect, and be sharpened by
the word and one another. Whether you
are a seasoned student of the word or
just starting your journey, there's a
seat for you at the table. Come curious,
leave encouraged. And so you can access
also being a part of gyms at sent gyms
gms at 855207417.
Our 10-minute ministry spotlight. Uh
this will be taking place as well. Uh we
are excited about that. And this is
where you get a chance to uh share and
record. This is what we want you to do.
Take the opportunity to record yourself.
just giving a little bit if you're a
ministry here um your ministry leader
just take the opportunity just to share
a few minutes of your experience as a
ministry leader what's happening with
your ministry and we're going to compile
all of those videos and uh we'll share
them with pastor Mike but also share
with the church as well and we'll be
able to spotlight your ministry here and
how you are working as part of the
living organism here of living mana
church we're excited about that
our living mana church global
YouTube channel is growing, growing,
growing and we are able to now I think
point at this point seven at least seven
plus languages that we are able to share
the sermons and the messages uh that
pastor Myers is giving in multiple
languages and today we're going to give
you just a little snippet of one of
those languages today.
Speech. Speech. Speech.
Say you
I'm I'm always blown away. I promise
you. It's almost as if I'm looking at
Pastor M's lips. I know this man does
not speak Arabic, but the way it's
translated and the way we're able to do
this through technology is absolutely
mind-blowing to me. And the same passion
is conveyed even through the scripture
text. So what we're hearing in English,
they are hearing exactly in their
language. And so what a what an
opportunity God is using to get the
three angels message out across the
world in various languages. And so we
actually thank you once again for your
support. Um, we'll make sure to let you
know how you can continue to help grow
that channel and continue to support how
we get translators to make sure we get
everything out in their real language to
get the gospel of Jesus Christ out
there. So, this is the way that you help
support the church on a weekly basis is
through going to Advent giving. You guys
are so amazing. um the way you support
not just the local church here at Living
Mana Church, but on a global level, you
you're so wonderful at going to
Adventist Church and
Adventistgiving.com.
And when you go there, you'll see a
virtual envelope pop up. And when you
see that virtual envelope pop up, you'll
see where you can give your tithe, your
uh offering to Living Matter Church, but
stays here locally. help supports the
ministries here, the technology,
everything we need to make sure that
this church is functioning um at a high
level and we're continuing to uh make
developments and with here within Living
Matter Church to make sure we get the
messages out here. Um you'll see other
areas where you can support benevolence
and write within there. You'll see areas
that are blank um that actually you can
write in which departments do you would
like to support. You can put uh any do
dollar amount you want to put in there.
You can write in there for for example,
hey, I want to support Living Mana Kids.
I want to support Living Mana Global,
which is the opportunity for you to put
right in there your dollars working to
get the ministry out, not just here at
Living Matter, but across the world. So,
make sure you can fill that in there as
well. and um for education. So, it
whatever it is you'd like, it is there
for you to get the word out to help us
and supporting the church and we're
excited about that. But if you can't do
that from a digital platform, you can do
that by writing a check. And when you do
that, you can also do the same thing,
but you will send the check, make it out
to Living Mana Church, sending it to PO
Box 248, Owens Crossroads, Alabama
35763.
And please make sure that you put at the
memo section or include a note when
you're mailing in your check what is
tithe, what is offering,
as well as what is sedition additional
ministries that you like your funds
applied to. I can tell you that your
funds are handled with 100% integrity
here. So, uh, we really are so grateful
for the financial support that you give
every single Sabbath, every single week
to help get the message out of Jesus
Christ. Um,
so in the meantime, uh, we want to take
this opportunity, uh, to serve and pray
and lift up and share. And so, right
now, let's go ahead and pray.
Let us pray. Um, heavenly father, uh,
thank you so much for the blessing of
the Sabbath day. We thank you for this
time of the sacred spot in the service,
Lord, for us to retire, return a
faithful tithe and offering. And thank
you so much that the funds are going as
everyone has designed for it to go to
share the gospel of Jesus Christ to be a
blessing to others through benevolence,
through education, through the uh
expanding and growing of the living mana
global channel and all the ministries
and auxiliaries here Lord to help bring
support to them. We thank you so much
also for the bread, the fresh bread that
Pastor Myers left for us. This is a new
sermon, a new message. And so we thank
you for what you're about to hear. We
ask your blessing even now upon everyone
that will be listening. May our hearts,
our minds be in tune and connected with
your spirit. We thank you. Thank you for
the privilege you've given us to serve
you. Thank you for this global family.
It is an honor to be a part of it. In
Jesus name I pray. Amen. All right. God
bless you all. Have a wonderful Sabbath.
God bless you. God bless you.
What happens in here
isn't meant to stay in here.
The hope we find in here isn't meant to
stay in here.
The grace we receive in here, the
victory we proclaim in here, the revival
that begins in here isn't meant to stay
in here. Our faith is made for movement.
Our testimony is designed to be told.
This place with these people, this is
the church. And what we do in here can
change the world out there.
We celebrate freedom in here so we can
carry freedom out there. We pray for
healing in here so we can bring healing
out there. We tell the stories of God's
goodness, God's peace, and God's love in
here so we can be the story of God's
goodness, God's peace, and God's love
out there. This is no ordinary place.
This is the body of Christ. A chosen
people with a holy purpose brought to
life by Jesus and sent out by Jesus. We
gather here, we confess here, we worship
here because what we do in here can
change the world out there.
What's up everybody? We're Brotherhood
Music. Massive shout out to Elevate
Studios for having us here to jam out
this song called Open The Eyes. We pray
and hope that it blesses you guys out
there as much as it blesses us.
[Music]
Open the eyes of my heart, Lord.
Open the eyes of my heart.
I want to see
you.
I want to see you.
[Music]
Open the eyes of my heart, Lord.
Open the eyes of my heart.
I want to see
you.
to see you high lifted
up,
shining in the light of your glory.
Pour out your power and love
as we sing holy, holy,
holy
to see you. I lift it up.
Shining in the light of your glory.
Pour out your power and love
as we sing. Holy, holy, holy.
I want to see
you.
I want to see.
[Music]
Open the eyes of my heart, Lord.
Open the eyes of my heart.
I want to see
you.
[Music]
Open the eyes of my heart, Lord.
Open the eyes of my heart.
I want to see
you.
[Music]
I want to see
you. Oh, to see you. I am lift it up
again.
Shining in the light of your glory.
Pour out, pour out your power and love
as we sing holy, holy,
holy to see you high and lift it up. Oh,
shining in the light of your glory.
Pour out, pour out your power and love
as we sing. Holy, holy,
holy, holy,
holy.
I want to see
you.
[Music]
I want to see
you.
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
[Music]
Amen. Amen. Praise the Lord everybody.
Happy Sabbath, saints of the most high
God. Welcome to another edition of
Living Manners Prayer and Praise Time.
I'm here with my lovely bride Amra. So
thankful. So thankful for that and
thankful for you saints. Good to see you
all. I hope you all have been blessed
and encouraged so far as you're enjoying
your day with God. Uh we've seen so many
of you in the chat. Usually we get to
have you shout out where you from. We
don't want you to do that. What we do
want you to do today though, if you
believe that God is using your life or
the lives of somebody else you know
around you to be a testimony and a
witness, no matter what's going on, no
matter what you see, no matter what you
hear, no matter what you feel, I want
you to just put a one in the chat and
say, "Yeah, God is God is building that
testimony."
>> Amen.
>> Elder Roberty Plant, we see you there.
Love you, my brother.
>> Hello, Crystal.
>> Everybody, shout outs to everybody.
Sister Mary Stella Johnson, we see you
in the chat.
>> Sister Nicole, love you. You've been
doing a wonderful job, sis. Keep on.
Sister Ashley Owens, love you. Welcome
to the living man of prayer team and
everything. You already on fire doing
what you do. You and your beautiful
family. We're looking forward to
spending some times with you. Uh here
comes the ones.
>> Cynthia Flowers, Colleen.
>> Yes. Testimon.
>> Jessica Graham.
>> Testimonies.
Yep. Yep. Yep.
>> I love the song by Carpenter. Hello.
Hello. Hello. God is good.
>> Yes. I love that song by Elder Robert uh
Marvin Saps. Just so glad I made it. So
glad I made it through. God is building
our testimony, saints. That's what he's
doing.
Amen. Amen.
>> Thank you, Denise. It's good to see
everyone as well.
>> Denise, who is Denise? Denise
>> to it. Oh, Denise to it. Happy Sabbath,
beloved sister. Denise Richardson is
another Denise. Happy Sabbath to you, my
sister. Jackie and Danny, I haven't seen
much of y'all in chat today, but I know
you're here. Happy Sabbath.
>> Hello, Jamie. Hello, Tiffany. Hello,
Leslin.
>> Everybody look at these testimonies.
>> Olive, Shaunene,
>> come on. Testimonies.
Sister Olive is here.
>> Hello, Patrice.
>> Don't Don't worry. I'm about to get to
Patrice in a minute. Sister Patrice and
the production team. Love y'all. Brother
Josh, just love it, man. Chuckling with
you. Joshua, Son of Viviveror, we love
you. Uh, Brother Gavin, we love you back
there. Brother Colin, all y'all holding
it down. Thank you for everything that
you do. But, Sister Patrice, our
producer, I mean, just wonderful gift to
the church. We love you, Sister Patrice.
Sister Patrice, that was me that uh made
that little sound when you were doing
the announcements. So, my bad, but uh,
you know,
thank you so much, Sister Patrice. love
you. Uh uh uh just can't say enough. Uh
give our love to Shelby. We pray that
God's continuing to bless and move in
her life as we're praying and believing
for her and the rest of your family.
Also, you know what? Um
there was uh the Mercer's testimony.
That was something. I know we've seen it
before. I know y'all have seen it
before. I'm not going to talk long today
because we have a praise report we want
to share with y'all. But and then
brother Kashif's going to come and lead
us in as in intercessory prayer. So I'm
just going to say a couple things that
was on my heart. First of all, happy
anniversary to pastor and first lady.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> We pray that y'all are enjoying
yourselves and and if you if you're not
tuned in right now, you can tune in
later. Uh we're recording. We're live
now. But our love to you. Uh we want you
to know we're thinking about you. Not
the same without you here. Can't wait
till you get back so we can have that
beautiful uh panel that we have on the
Christian art of war with the M&M's and
with brother Kashib. Pastor Lo Amy, love
you and yours and uh Sister Kennedy,
hope you're back with us and just
looking forward to that. But but in the
meantime, enjoy yourselves where you
are.
>> We love you, Ivorante, very much.
>> Amen. You know, we wouldn't be right
here if you guys hadn't been right
there. Exactly. So, thank God. We are
celebrating you and the love God has
given you. You're a beautiful example to
a lot of us and an inspiration
definitely to us. So,
>> absolutely.
>> You're more than just our pastor, but
you're our friends. You're more than
just our friends, but you're our family.
So, we thank God for you. Be blessed.
All right. What else? I wanted to shout
out Sister Nicole. You're doing a great
work here at Living Mana Hangouts.
>> That was so fun last week. Look,
>> look. I know some of y'all be like, "Oh,
I see the announcement about Hangouts."
No, you missed it. If you weren't there,
you missed it.
>> But you have another chance
>> on the 7th, I believe.
>> Yes.
>> I'm going to tell y'all something. Y'all
missed. If you didn't come, and I know a
lot of y'all didn't. So, we're praying
for you.
>> We learned a lot.
>> We're not going to try to guilt you into
coming, right? But you missed it. Okay.
>> It It was a lot of fun. I'm telling you,
>> it was We learned so much about each
other.
>> They did such a great job. Nicole did
such a great job. We had the videos with
Sister Angela and Sister Denise and
everybody, you know, and
>> we played two truths and what did they
call it?
>> No, no, no. One truth, right? No. And a
fiction. Oh, okay.
>> Two truths.
>> Two truths and a fairy tale. See, we
don't call it We don't use the other
word here, right? We
>> two truths and a not so true. Okay. Is
that
>> That's how That's great. Yeah.
>> Yes. That was fun. And we learn a lot
about one another. You know, Sister
Denise has this quote. She says, you
know, we know how to pray together, but
we need to learn how to play together.
>> Exactly.
>> And I And now that's so true, you know,
because we come in and we know how to do
church and we're all stuck up and you
know, we go to Well, we're not stuck up
at Living Mana, but you know, we do
churchy stuff, right? But there you can
let your hair down. Those of you who
have it, but you can you can have a good
time and just hang out, get to know each
other. I learned some stuff about some
people. I really Travis, getting to know
you was really interesting. Mary,
getting to know you. Brother Phillip is
just an absolute adventure.
>> We were all put in small groups, so we
kind of got to know our little cluster
and then I'm sure that we'll be put into
small groups again next week to get to
know other people better. It was so
>> It was
>> great. So, please come next week.
>> Please do. Jody, I saw you there. Our
sister Jod, I saw I remember seeing you.
I saw
>> I think there was about 30 people that
showed up last week.
>> Yeah, it was our This is our uh hangout
plug. We weren't really planning on
>> I was because I when I when I left there
I said, "Look, Hangouts all right."
>> It was fun.
>> It was all right. It was a lot of fun.
So, don't miss it. The seventh. We're
going to keep shouting them out. They're
doing a great job. Beautiful stuff.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
>> Yes. Two truths and a makeelieve. That's
what they called it.
>> Yeah. That's Yeah. So, if you guys
haven't heard about that,
you kind of share two truths about
yourself and then something that's made
up and people have to guess which which
of those things is made up, which is
harder than you would think. But
>> yeah, and I don't want to get too far
into it, but Sister Joanne just shocked
everybody with her truth. Nobody could
believe it.
>> No one could believe my truths either,
>> right? But we're not gonna tell you, but
you got to come. You want to find out.
learn about one another and it's really
cool. And also I want to say that bumper
that video um what stays I mean what
happens in here
doesn't just stay in here man that's all
right Vegas doesn't try to steal that
what happens in Vegas stays in Vegas
right it need to stay there but what
happens here needs to be shared out
there God's blessing you tell somebody
about it and that's one of the reasons
why we need to love one another and we
need to learn how to get along we need
to see redemption taking place we need
to see reconciliation we need to see
forgiveness we need to see love we need
to see all of that because when that
happens here. We can share that out
there. Yes.
>> But when we biting and diving, tearing
one another apart up in here, believe
me, they going to hear about it out
there. It happens. It It don't stay
here. Nothing. So anyway,
>> thank you, Jodie Mccclure. I saw what
you said.
>> Okay. What?
>> She said Amber and I were in the same
group and I learned some amazing,
inspiring things about her.
>> Yes. Well, Amber's an amazing person. A
lot to
>> Oh my gosh, y'all gonna make me blush up
here.
>> Okay. Spamco, I wanted to shout out
Spamco as our brother in Serbia. Brother
Seaminko, brother Spamco, thank you,
brother. What a blessing it is. And
we're honored to have you a part of LOC.
Uh we thank you that you're here. We're
praying for you. We love you. Continue
to plug in and continue to be a
blessing. I think he was there too at
the hangouts, I believe. Yes, you were.
You were at the hangouts. Also, one more
thing about hangouts. They need hosts,
>> brothers. Men, rise up, men. Come on.
Cuz that's right. Men, get involved.
Come on. And uh help out with Hangouts.
You're going to see it's really, really
amazing. I'm telling you.
>> Okay,
>> Majesca. Last thing I'm going to say,
and I'm going to hand it over to you, my
love.
>> Okay,
>> Majesca, we love you. We're blessed to
have you. Thank you so much uh for being
a part of this beautiful LC family. We
thank you for your labors of love and
all that you do. We're continuing to
pray with you and for you. Uh the
victory is yours, my dear sister. The
victory is yours. Uh after we do the
praise reports, I'm going to say one
thing about that victory and then we're
going to go to the throne of grace. Hey
Shereice Henley, love you my sister. H
what a gift. What a gift. Shereice, see
you there.
>> Praise reports.
>> I have quite a few. Um so let's get into
it. First, just a reminder. If you have
a prayer request or you have a praise
report that you would like to submit or
you would like to join us on the prayer
team or join a special ops prayer team
group.
>> Amen.
>> Please send an email to pray living
manana.urch.
If you would like to request a special
ops team for yourself or a loved one,
please send an email to spec ops, that's
sops
at livingmana.urch.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry, please send an email to women
livingmana.urch. And finally, if you
would like to join the men's ministry,
please send an email to seven loaves.
That's s ven l o a ve livingmanana.urch.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> All right.
First praise report coming from Vivian
Shelton. Thanks so much for praying for
my daughter Sabrina Quinn. Her cancer is
clear now. Thank God for his healing.
Nothing is too hard for God.
From Artel Peters. God is good all the
time and all the time God is good. Well,
amen. He sure is. Through my reliance on
the Holy Spirit that was sent by his son
so that his mission would continue, my
surgery was completed and my strength
was facilitated by the prayers of my LOC
members. Thank you, my heavenly father.
>> Amen.
>> From Jamie Grace, thank you so much for
praying. Glory to God. Today I'm feeling
much better. No more pain from my dental
extraction or migraine. Praise the Lord.
Amen.
>> From Graham Henry. Thanks for the
prayers. Muriel was freed and cleared
for discharge. She started back to work.
Praise God.
>> Praise God.
>> From Olivia Torres, aka Olive. No, no,
it's Olive aka Olivia.
>> Okay.
>> Olive or Olivia. Okay. God took over and
taking care of the AC issues. My new
tenant is no longer fixated on the
thermostat. No word from her. So, I take
that as good news. Praise God.
>> With the grace of God, my handyman took
care of some aesthetic issues, which is
very minimal. And my car is able to
charge the gear from park to drive and
reverse.
Moving forward, I thank God for guiding
me in what steps to take and be a light
to those who are in darkness. I trust
you, Father God, for you never
disappoint. Thank you, saints, for all
the prayers. Thank you, God. Marvelous
indeed are your works.
>> Amen. from Majeshka.
We got the internet back in the final
hours of Sabbath. Pray Praise God I was
able to join just after all the
technical problems. Amen. From Teresa
Hatton. Praise God that DJ has been
accepted into college. He starts
September 3rd. Please keep the Hatton
family in prayer.
>> Amen. That's good news.
>> That is great news. Praise God.
>> Amen. Amen. from L'Oreal Moore.
The prayer was, "Please pray for my
husband who may lose his job. He has
sleep apnea and it is difficult for him
to stay up during the night shift." But
the praise report, "My husband got a
call from his supervisor. He will be
able to keep his job."
>> Praise God.
>> Thank you for the prayers. We really
appreciate it. From Kela, today I came
here to thank all for the prayers for my
shoulder. I am 90% better and mostly
pain-free. All praises to our Lord Jesus
for the blessing of healing that I so
desperately needed.
>> From Annette Rivas, good morning family.
I have a praise report on August 14th. I
put this prayer request in the chat.
Please help me pray over my son Daniel's
work situation. He got hired as a
seasonal worker for the city and it is
coming to an end. He is two weeks to
find another job. May God lead him to
the job that will help him bring him
honor and glory to his name. Amen.
>> Praise report. I am so happy to announce
that my son started a wonderful job with
excellent benefits this week. He will be
exercising his welding skills and he is
also going to be a plumber apprentice
which is another wonderful trade to
learn. God is so good. Thank you all for
helping me pray. Amen.
>> From Ashley Owens, the prayer request.
Dear friends, I would deeply appreciate
your prayers today. I have a very
important doctor's appointment at the
pain clinic. This is my second time
seeing this doctor, and I felt she
doubted my conditions at my first visit.
I'm asking the Lord to go before me
today to soften her heart, give me
favor, and allow my progress to be seen.
By God's grace, I have already great
greatly reduced my medication since
February and lost over 37 pounds through
diet, fasting, and exercise since April.
Congratulations. That's a praise in
itself.
>> Yes,
>> my goal is to one day be free of all
medications, but right now I still need
transitional support so I can keep
moving forward instead of being
restricted to my bed. Please pray that
the Lord will guide this appointment.
Give me peace and that he will his will
be done. I'm clinging to his promise.
Fear thou not, for I am with thee, but
not to spade. For I am thy God. I will
strengthen thee. Yay, I will help thee.
Yay, I will uphold thee with the right
hand of my righteousness. Thank you so
much for lifting me up today. And the
praise report. My appointment went well.
The doctor was impressed with my
progress and is willing to work with me
as on a transitional plan. Thank you for
your prayers. And then finally, I just
wanted to say I got a pretty lengthy
praise report from someone who would
like to remain anonymous regarding
someone who we will be calling P.
And I will be reading that next week. So
hang tight. If I wasn't able to get to
your prayer uh praise reports today, I
will be covering them next week because
>> we have a special guest today who would
like to share their own praise report.
So, please welcome Gigi Jones who would
like to share her praise report with us
today.
>> Amen.
>> Hi everybody. Oh, look at you looking
all summery and beautiful.
>> GG.
>> Look at you, girl. Okay,
>> go do it. Go do it. That's that's high
praises coming from coming from you. But
yeah, we we here to praise the Lord now.
Come on. Um, so first of all, happy
Sabbath everybody. Um,
I am here to talk about a praise report
that started back in January. Um the
prayer request was that I was having a
terrible allergic reaction. I had boils
like like Joe boils all over um from a
supplement I was taking to lose weight.
Um
I had heard about it. It was all natural
and and um it was a combination of three
supplements and I checked with the
doctor and they were like, "No, these
are really great and stuff and there's
the one in particular was especially
great for people with Hashimoto's,
thyroid issues." And so I was like,
"Yeah, let's do it." Well, the one of
them reacted really poorly with another
condition that I had and I had these
boils. Uh the praise uh I'm sorry the
prayer request was you know obviously
for healing. Um healing didn't come and
I had several doctor's appointments and
they put me on antibiotics. Now this is
January. Um
throughout the throughout the next few
weeks healing would I would get healing
um here and there
of the boils and they get better and I'd
be like praise God. Praise God. sending
in prayer request, quick to send in a
praise report. Hey, they're getting
better. Thank you so much. I'm feeling
better. Um, but weeks would go by and
they would it would flare up again. It
just wasn't going away all the way. Um,
at one and I'd go into the doctor and
now keep in mind I I really love my
doctor. um she's one of the few people
who would take me seriously and so I
really love her but she for some reason
in this particular thing was a little I
want to say apathetic and was just like
yeah that okay and just kept putting me
on antibiotics now I followed I follow
Dr. Kenisha and I'm like getting worried
about my gut health and so I I keep
going in. At one point they actually
clear up um and come right back again.
Every time I think I've been healed and
I'm giving praise reports,
it would come back. Um it I it just
wasn't going away. Um at one point
pastor prayed for me and almost
overnight they had shrunk down and I was
like this is it. Prayers of a righteous
avail much. This is it. I even text him.
Oh my goodness. Like that anointing is
something else. Um but came back flared
right back up. I just couldn't get past
it. U my doctor sent me to a
dermatologist.
The dermatologist
was
again not just not understanding how
painful they were. um that my job I sit
down a lot and
they were in the area that I sit with
and um it was very painful,
uncomfortable. I couldn't I couldn't I
wasn't getting any sleep cuz I couldn't
get comfortable and he again continued
the antibiotics. Um so this is going on
for a couple months now that I'm
actually on antibiotics. Um the most of
the boils end up clearing up again.
Praise report. Yay. Although I'm still
in the back of my head kind of like are
they going to come back? But they did.
But there was one in particular that I
don't know what you would call it, but
it was almost like a stone.
Um it was a hard hard substance. Um
probably about this big and it was a
stone underneath my skin and um it it I
don't want to get too gross or anything.
was draining this and that, but the
dermatologist was like, "Um,
listen, there's there's not too much I
can do. I'm going to send you to a
specialist." And I was like, "Okay. Um,
what is he going to do?" He's like,
"Well, you're going to have to have
surgery to have it out." And in the
meantime, I'm I'm really in a lot of
pain. I'm freaking out because I just I
have a kind of a phobia about things
being on me or in me or anything. um and
they just kind of keep sending you home
with this kind of like, yeah, it's
whatever. So, the day after that last
appointment um with the dermatologist
and they sending me a referral to this
to the specialist
um it just blows up to this this this
rock this rock-l like thing in me blows
up to the side to the size of a golf
ball and
a piece of it breaks off and the whole
thing becomes inflamed
um while I'm on antibiotics
and
I don't know what to do now. There's
there's the stone and there's a piece
and it's all it's all super inflamed and
I so I call them and the nurse won't let
me talk to the doctor. I'm like I I just
was there yesterday and he told me I
would be fine that that you know things
were getting better and it's now the
size of a golf ball. Um and she was very
apathetic and very like what do you want
me to do about it? Um then she came back
to me and said, "Well, we'll put you on
antibiotics." I said, "No, you don't
understand. This happened while I'm on
antibiotics."
Um and and I'm getting a little
I'm getting I'm getting very upset at
this point because I' I've been more
patient and kind than I than I thought I
was capable of when I was in a lot of
pain and sick. And so I'm feeling like
that that point where you're you you're
getting ready to get pushed over your
limit and break. And I'm just like,
"Ma'am,
um, and she says, "Well, the best we can
do is make their make the referral
urgent." And I was like, "Oh, okay.
Urgent, great. So they're going to call
me right away." And then she's like,
"Well, we can't control that. We are
just going to make it urgent."
Okay. So, um, I get a call from, um, the
urgency was about a week later. I got a
call from the the surgeon office and
they this was in now in April, so it's
January to April. They could not get me
in
until um September.
Um and I was like, "Ma'am, um I know
this is your first time talking to me,
but I cannot stay on antibiotics from
for now. This will be going on 9
months." I was like, I I I I can't.
you're killing my gut health. I was
like, I cannot live with this golf ball
sized thing inside of me. I like I got
to I'm going away for the summer to do
very physical work. I I I I was just
like this cannot happen. This is how I'm
going to pay for my school. Like I just
saw this domino effect happening about
losing my job, this and that because I
can't get these people to understand
that this is my it's not just it's not
just this problem. this is my life. It's
going to cause a lot of issues. And she
was just like, "Yeah, that's really the
best we can do. Um, I can put you on a
waiting list." I was like, "Ma'am,
please, you know, please, I'm talking to
human to human at this point. Um, the
wait the waiting list isn't going to
work because I'm going to be in
Minnesota and if you call me to tell me
to come in, can't really make it back
down to Texas in time." Um, it's like
really there's just nothing we can do
for you. And
I wanted there every bit of my flesh was
like just wanting to tee off on this
woman and and be like, "How can you be
so uncaring?" Um,
but I was just like, "Okay, thank you.
Thank you." Somehow the Holy Spirit had
my tongue. All right. Thank you so much.
I appreciate it. And I just there was
nothing else I could do. And I just
prayed to God. It continuously coursed
through this whole time, but just was
like, God, what do you want me to do?
Like,
I I just don't know. I How am I gonna
do? How am I going to drive from Texas
to Minnesota
with this on my bottom? Like, how sit
for all this time? How am I going to do
a physical how how how?
And God just impressed upon me too that
the one thing that Joseph kept doing in
every situation, he kept serving. He
kept working. So, every day I would just
keep it moving, keep it going. So, I'm
going to get to the praise report. Um, I
went I did go most of you know I did go
to the internship for the summer. I'm
just getting back. And
again, I I just hit the road. Didn't
didn't know how I was going to make it
there, how I was going to do anything.
Just kept kept going. Um, but I did and
I made it back. Um, I was talking to
brother Terry and he was sharing with me
um, a updates on Amira. And as he was
talking to me, the Lord kind of just re
reminded me and revealed to me a lot of
the parallels in in our stories,
although hers is Katie Stone and
obviously much more serious. Um,
and I realized that
I don't need that. I've been this it
hadn't I don't know when I can't even
tell you when exactly it got healed but
I don't have that anymore. Not only
don't I have it. There's no scar.
There's no little lump. There's no bump.
There's no nothing. It's gone. And I
didn't even realize it until I was
talking to brother Terry. It is
completely gone. Um,
I wish I could tell you that I prayed
big prayers, that I went into my prayer
closet, that I fasted and prayed, that I
did I did all this stuff.
I just gave it to God, surrendered, and
kept working. Um, and I didn't even
realize it. And the verse that he
brought to mind was Isaiah 65:17.
So, see, I will create new heaven and
new earth. the former things will not be
remembered, nor will they come to mind.
Um, I didn't even I didn't even remember
having it. And I firmly I just believe
with all my heart that that's out there
for somebody that this whatever trauma,
whatever sickness you're going through,
whatever that seems like this is your
life right now and you're just kind of
resigned to it. There's going to come a
time where you don't even remember that
version of yourself. You're so busy or
doing other stuff for the Lord. you're
so praising him about all this other
stuff going on that that blessing is
just going to you won't even have a scar
to remember it by and so um right now
what you're going to see so that I went
and looked to see when that appointment
was um for exactly because I didn't
remember it is for Wednesday September
3rd uh so this is when the Lord pressed
put it on my part to ask brother Terry
and Amra if I could give this praise
report. Um, and it put it on my heart
that for for this Sabbath. I didn't even
realize it was the Sabbath before my
appointment. And so, y'all going to see
me right now cancel
that appointment because I don't need
it. Um, God healed me. And thank you all
for your prayers. Um,
>> I love you all so much. And yeah,
>> thank you for listening and having me
here.
>> Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow.
>> Amen. Praise God. Come on, Living Man
and give God praise.
>> Thank you for sharing that. I
>> I actually have a copy of that
appointment too right here by the way. I
I saw it. Um and listen, normally we we
we we don't take this much time during
the prayer session. But listen, God is
doing something.
>> It doesn't matter who you are and where
you are and what you're going through.
We're getting ready to go to the throne
of grace. But when we go with this kind
of encouragement and this kind of
confidence, God can move mountains.
>> Absolutely.
>> I remember some things that were going
on with me for 25 years in prison. And
let me tell you, some of them days and
some of them worries and some of them
aggravations and some of them things
that was about to make me lose my mind.
I can't even remember those things. Of
course, I got some new things to worry
about now. So, yeah, but God lose his
mind.
>> God Yeah. All the time. All the time.
All the time. God is good. Listen, be
encouraged, saints of the most high God.
Be encouraged. Be encoura That's right.
Look at God. Somebody, I see you in the
chat. Our God is able. It don't feel
like it in the middle of it. Y'all know
what I'm talking about. When you feel
like cussing and spitting, giving
somebody a piece of your mind. Don't do
it. Keep it. We need all our mind,
right? But God is good.
>> Yes, he is.
>> He is good. He is. And so, be
encouraged. I was talking to Denise
yesterday. She say, "Everybody on the
prayer team under attack." I said, "No,
we're not under nothing." The Bible
says, "We're raised up to sit together
in heavenly places in Christ Jesus, far
above all principality, power, might,
and dominion, and every name that is
named." And you know, Ephesians 6:12
said, "That's what we're wrestling
against. Principalities and powers and
rulers of the darkness of this present
evil world, spiritual wickedness in
heavenly place." The Bible said, we
already above them. Like brother Kirk
always loves to say it. We're fighting
from a position of victory, saints. We
have that victory already. Amen.
>> And so, come on, somebody and be
encouraged as brother Kashib comes and
takes us to the throne of grace. Brother
Kashif, we going with you, my brother.
>> We going with you today by the grace of
God as you come and lead this church in
intercessory prayer.
>> Hello, Kashif.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Hello. Hello. Hello.
>> Amen. Mighty warrior.
what I'm doing from my phone today. And
for whatever reason, the camera is um
>> Oh, it's okay. It's all right.
>> That's all right. We see you, brother.
>> All right. All right.
All right, church. Um it's just like
brother Terry said, you know, um that is
so powerful to, you know, just put all
your trust in God and he will he can
literally heal you like we read in the
Bible cuz it just happened with Sister
Gigi.
>> Amen. So, um, let's keep believing and
let's go into prayer.
Father in heaven, we thank you, Lord,
for your wonderful Sabbath. We thank you
for those praise reports. We thank you
for always showing how faithful you are,
Lord. We thank you for encouraging us in
the faith. We thank you for blessing us.
We thank you for protecting us, Lord.
God, most of all, we thank you for
showing us how to love others like you
love us, Father.
Father, I just want to lift up our
sister Takara who's praying for a friend
Van. Um, he probably has a stronghold,
Lord. And we pray that you you help him
to overcome and that you're able to that
he's able to see the working of your
Holy Spirit in his life, Lord. Lord, I
also pray that you help our sister with
to be more kind, more patient, and she's
praying to be more merciful and more
forgiving. Lord, Lord, that is something
that we all need to come to you for a
refreshing of that every single day. And
we know that only your Holy Spirit can
give that to us, Lord. So, Father, I
thank you for our sister Takar who
reminds us of this with this prayer
request.
Lord, I thank you for sister Teresa
Hatton as well. We thank you for DJ
getting into college. He's going to
start college soon. We continue to pray
for this entire family, Lord. Lord, help
us not to think in terms of time because
you're everlasting. So, as long as it
takes, we will continue to pray and lift
up this family. Father, Lord, we pray
for sister Annie who's um in need of
healing, of pain and recovery. Lord, I
pray that you um you touch her body and
help her to experience the same joy that
our sister Gigi is experiencing right
now. Our father
about sister Tony who's praying for her
brother Charlie recovering from heart
surgery.
Lord we thank you that we live in a time
where heart surgery can even be
performed to prolong life. Lord Lord we
we know that everything is according to
your will. So father I ask you to touch
his body and help him in this recovery.
Lord bring him back to 100% health. I
pray the same for Deb who's recovering
from brain surgery as well.
be seen the things that you can do and
the brain might bring fear with regards
to recovery and people wondering if you
would come back to 100%.
So Lord, I I just pray that you work the
way that you want to work in Debbiey's
life. Lord, I thank you for doing this
well. I lift up Shannon and Tony's son
um who's dealing with alcohol addiction.
Lord, and Father, we know that you are
stronger and you are bigger than any
addiction, any stronghold, anything of
those sorts that the enemy tries to
steal us with, Lord. So, Father, I ask
you to send your Holy Spirit into their
lives and give them that one moment of
clarity where they're able to just give
it up, Lord, because they've given it to
you, Father. Father, I pray for the
husband as well who is experiencing
lower back pain. We ask you to place
your healing touch on his back so that
he can be relieved. You can take it away
from him completely.
I lift up his thyroid biopsy that he's
having that it'll be free of cancer and
know that all praise can be given to
you. Father, lift up Lisa Clark who's
having whose mom is having heart
palpitations, you know, unexpectedly and
unexplained.
So Lord, I just pray that whether it be
stress or anxiety or anything to do with
the heart itself, Lord, I pray for
wisdom and guidance. I ask you for
clarity for and for Lisa as well, Lord.
Lord, I lift up um Sister Jod's request
as well who's you know just praying for
all the members and faith members of
this church who's recently experienced
any type of loss. Lord, Father, it's
easy to fall into despair and we know
the enemy is always looking to
capitalize on these things. So, Father,
I I thank you for this prayer requ this
this prayer request that
we are able to come to you and encourage
one another. Lord, I thank you for the
love that you've shown. I thank you for
the love that we're seeing in this
church. Lord, Lord, I ask that Ivonne
who has an unspoken request, but she's
feeling depressed. Lord, Father, again,
we speak against the enemy again, that
he will have no grip on her life and on
her mind. Lord, I pray that you lead her
into
just praising you, Lord, just saying,
because singing your praises really does
change a mood. And Lord, I thank you for
her being brave enough to put this
request even though we don't know what
it is, but you know what it is, Lord.
And for everyone else who is
experiencing any type of mental agony or
heartbreak or just being burdened, Lord,
I pray that you would cover them with
your love and comfort them and help them
to understand the way in which you love
them, Lord. Because when we truly
understand that, there isn't anything
else that could have us feeling any type
of negative way, Lord. So, Father, I
thank you for blessing this church. I
thank you for covering them. Lord, I ask
you to keep them focused on your word
and through study and prayer that we're
able to have your Holy Spirit dwelling
in our hearts. Lord, thank you for
hearing and answering this prayer in
Jesus name. Amen.
Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> So we are thankful to God for an
exciting time of prayer today. Saints of
the most high God and we are thank God
for brother Kashie, sister Gigi and all
of you. And today evangelism Sabbath
want to encourage you all to know that
you are living epistles. You're a
testimony in the making. Be encouraged.
Somebody needs to hear your story,
saints. Somebody needs to hear your
story. So, don't be encouraged by the
trials you're going through. The Bible
tells us, "Think it not a strange thing
concerning the fiery trials that's going
to come upon you. God is doing something
in you.
>> You may be in the fire right now,
somebody watching, but he's purifying.
He's purging. He's making you. You're
going to come through like pure gold.
Can we say amen?
>> Your test will become a testimony.
>> Amen. Every time. Every time. So, be
encouraged, saints. Our God is real. I
see you in the chat, folks. Amen. Amen.
And so, as we prepare for the word of
God, buckle up. Uh uh we're we're going
to the Pastor Myers is going to be
bringing a word about the Lord's day,
and we are praying, God, anoint this
word. May it touch the hearts and minds
and lives of your people, Lord. May
their cup spill over into their world
around them in Jesus mighty and glorious
name.
>> Amen.
[Music]
The Lord bless you
and keep you.
Make his face shine upon you and be
gracious to you. The Lord turn his
face toward you
and give you peace.
[Music]
The Lord bless you
and keep you.
Make his face shine upon you and be
gracious to you. The Lord turn his
face over you
and give you peace.
[Music]
Amen.
A Amen.
[Music]
Amen.
The Lord bless you
and keep you.
Make his face shine upon you and be
gracious to you. The Lord turn his
face for you
and give you peace.
Amen.
[Music]
Oh,
may his favor be upon you and a thousand
generations
and your family and your children and
their children and their children. May
his favor be upon you and a thousand
generations
and your family and your children and
their children and their children. May
his favor be upon you and a thousand
generations
and your family and your children and
their children and their children. May
his favor be upon you and a thousand
generations
and your family and your children and
their children and their children. May
his presence go before you and behind
you and beside you, all around you and
within you. He is with you. is with you
in the morning, in the evening, in your
coming, and you're going, and you're
weeping and rejoicing. He is for you. He
is for you. He's for you. He is for you.
He is for you. He's for you. He's for
you. He's for you. He's for you.
Oh.
Amen.
[Music]
[Applause]
Amen.
[Music]
Oh Jesus,
you go before us. God, you go before us.
Jesus,
>> you for us. You for us.
>> Yes, you are. Yes, you are.
>> He's for you. He's for you.
[Music]
May his favor be upon you and a thousand
generations
and your family and your children and
their children and their children. May
his presence go before you and behind
you and beside you, all around you and
within you. He is with you. He is with
you in the morning, in the evening, in
your coming, in your going, in your
weeping and rejoicing. He is for you. He
is for you.
[Music]
But I woke up.
No longer I who live.
Now Jesus lives in me. For I was dead in
sin, but I woke up to see the light.
Amen. And happy Sabbath. Welcome Living
Mana online church family. Uh we are
getting ready to get into the word of
God this morning. And if you are ready
and if you're excited, please put one in
the chat because uh I will let you know
right now the message that is going to
be preached today uh is highly
significant and highly relevant
especially to end time events. And so
today's message is entitled the day of
the Lord. And um we're going to see
exactly what this day of the Lord is and
not only what it is, but why it is. And
so with that said, we're going to have a
word of prayer. I'm going to get right
into the message. Let's do that now.
Heavenly Father, bless us Lord as we
open your word. I pray Lord in a very
special way that you would give your
people understanding. Lord, please speak
through your servant today. Is my prayer
in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
Beloved, the first thing that I want to
share with you as we go to the screen
for the message entitled the day of the
Lord is that there are three distinct
days of the Lord in the Bible. Three
distinct day of the Lords in the Bible.
Notice with me Isaiah 13:6.
The Bible says, "How ye, for the day of
the Lord is at hand. It shall come as a
destruction from the Almighty. Now, this
is the prophet Isaiah speaking. And the
question is, what is Isaiah referring to
as he's speaking to his own people,
Israel, and warning them of this day of
the Lord to come, this destruction from
the Almighty?
And the answer is is in its context
Isaiah is referring to the destruction
of Jerusalem by Babylon.
He is using prophetic language to
describe this destruction that that uh
Jerusalem will experience because of
their rejection of the Lord. And so what
you'll find is that in the Old
Testament, uh there are prophets that
are what we call pre-exilic meaning
these prophets
wrote before the destruction of
Jerusalem by Babylon. And they were all
warning of the same event. They were
warning Israel to repent, to return from
their wicked ways. uh uh otherwise this
day of the Lord would come upon them.
And that day of the Lord was the
destruction of Jerusalem by Babylon. And
so you'll notice with me the book of
Lamentations,
chapter 2, 21 and 22. The Bible says
here, "The young and the old lie on the
ground in the streets. My virgins and my
young men are fallen by the sword. Thou
hast slain them in the day of thine
anger. Thou has killed and not pied.
Thou has called as in the solemn day my
terrors round about so that in the day
of the Lord's anger none escaped nor
remained. Those that I have swallowed
and brought up have mine enemy consumed.
Again we find here this is in reference
to the same day of the Lord. We find it
again in Ezekiel 7:1 19.
They shall cast their silver in the
streets and their gold shall be removed.
Their silver and their gold shall not be
able to deliver them in the day of the
wrath of the Lord.
They shall not satisfy their souls,
neither fill their bowels because it is
the stumbling block of their iniquity.
Ezekiel was warning of the same thing.
We find it again in Ezekiel 13:5. It
says here, "You have not gone up into
the gaps, neither made up the hedge for
the house of Israel to stand in the
battle in the day of the Lord." We find
it again in Zephaniah 1 7 and 8. Hold
thy peace at the presence of the Lord
God, for the day of the Lord is at hand.
For the Lord has prepared a sacrifice.
He has bid his guests. And it shall come
to pass in the day of the Lord's
sacrifice that I will punish the princes
and the king's children and all such are
clothed with strange apparel. We'll look
at one more verse in this context.
Zephaniah 1 verse 14 and 15. The great
day of the Lord is near. It is near and
hasteth greatly. Even the voice of the
day of the Lord. The mighty man shall
cry there bitterly.
That day is a day of wrath, a day of
trouble and distress, a day of wastess
and desolation, a day of darkness and
glooiness, a day of clouds and thick
darkness. And so what I want you to
understand here is that we everything we
have laid out so far was in reference to
the first day of the Lord.
This is
referring to the children of Israel or
Jerusalem being destroyed by Babylon.
Now, we're we're laying the foundation
here for something absolutely
mind-blowing. So, so put a one in the
chat if you're following so far. The
simple point we have made thus far is
that the prophets who wrote before the
destruction of Jerusalem by Babylon
referred to that destruction as the day
of the Lord. Now I said there were three
days of the Lord in the Bible. We're
going to now go to the second day of the
Lord.
Now, this second day of the Lord, you're
going to find prominent in the prophets
who came after the destruction of
Jerusalem by Babylon. In other words,
after Jerusalem was set free from
Babylon and they went back to Jerusalem,
the Jews went back to Jerusalem, rebuilt
their city and their temple.
Now, you had a new set of prophets
rising, warning of another day of the
Lord. So notice with notice with me Joel
chapter 1 verse1 15 alas for the day
alas for the day for the day of the Lord
is at hand and as a destruction from the
Almighty shall it come. What day of the
Lord is Joel talking about here? Joel
chapter 2 verse one and two. Blow ye the
trumpet in Zion and sound an alarm in my
holy mountain. Let all the inhabitants
inhabitants of the land tremble, for the
day of the Lord cometh, for it is nigh
at hand. A day of darkness and
glooiness, a day of clouds and of thick
darkness, as the morning spread upon the
mountains. Joel here is referring to
another day of the Lord. And this one
has to be future of the one that
happened when Babylon destroyed
Jerusalem. This is another day of the
Lord that the children of Israel are
being warned about. Again,
we find this in Joel chapter 2:31.
The sun shall be turned into darkness
and the moon into blood before the great
and terrible day of the Lord. We find it
in Joel 3:14. Multitudes, multitudes in
the valley of decision, for the day of
the Lord is near in the valley of
decision. And then we find it in Malachi
chapter 4:es 1 and five. This is the
last book of the Old Testament. And
here's what it says. For behold, the day
cometh that shall burn as an oven, and
all the proud, yay, all that do wickedly
shall be stubble,
as the day that cometh shall burn them
up, sayith the Lord of hosts, that it
shall leave them neither root nor
branch. And notice verse five. Behold, I
will send you Elijah the prophet before
the coming of the great and dreadful day
of the Lord. These prophets who lived
after the destruction of Jerusalem by
Babylon
are warning of a second day of the Lord
to come. We find this as well in
Zechariah chapter 14 verse1. For behold,
the day of the Lord cometh and the spoil
shall be divided in the midst of thee.
So the question now is this.
What is this second day of the Lord that
these postexilic prophets are pointing
to? How what are they warning the Jews?
What kind of danger or destruction are
they warning the Jews about? What are
they saying is coming? Well, if you
remember
on the day of Pentecost when the Holy
Spirit is poured out upon Peter and the
disciples, you'll remember that Peter
stood up to to preach. And you'll
remember he said something very, very
interesting. In Acts chapter 2:14,
listen to what the Bible says here. But
Peter standing up with with the 11
lifted up his voice and said unto them,
"Ye men of Judah, and all ye that dwell
at Jerusalem." Be this known unto you,
and hearken to my words, for these are
not drunken as you suppose, seeing that
it is but the third hour of the day. Now
watch this.
But this is that which was spoken by the
prophet Joel. So this is the same
prophet we just read. The same prophet
that was talking about or warning about
this coming day of the Lord. Listen to
what it says here. This is that which
was spoken by the prophet Joel. And it
shall come to pass in the last days,
sayaith God. I will pour out my spirit
upon all flesh, and your sons and your
daughters shall prophesy, and your young
men shall see visions, and your old men
shall dream dreams. Here Peter
is using Joel to refer to the time that
he is in that Peter is speaking as the
last days. Now I know what you're
thinking. The last days? How could that
be the last days when
the world is still around today? What
last days was Peter saying was upon
Israel? Let's keep reading.
Acts chapter 2:1 18. And on my servants,
so he's still quoting Joel, "And on my
servants and on my handmmaids, I will
pour out in those days of my spirit, and
they shall prophesy. And I will show
wonders in heaven above, and signs in
the earth beneath, blood, and fire and
vapor of smoke. The sun shall be turned
into darkness, and the moon into blood
before the great and notable day of the
Lord come. And it shall come to pass
that whosoever shall call on the name of
the Lord shall be saved." And so
to make this plain,
the second day of the Lord that these
postexelic prophets were speaking about
was none other than the destruction of
Jerusalem by Rome.
This would have been the second day of
the Lord. The prophets are using endtime
language to point to the coming
destruction of Jerusalem. In fact, let's
go back to the book of Joel chapter 2
verse one and note what Peter is quoting
in Joel 2 vers1. It says, "Blow you the
trumpet in Zion and sound an alarm in my
holy mountain. Let all the inhabitants
of the land tremble, for the day of the
Lord cometh, for it is nigh at hand, a
day of darkness and of glooiness, a day
of clouds and of thick darkness, as the
morning spreads upon the mountains."
Watch this now.
a great people and a strong. There has
not ever been the like. Neither shall be
anymore after it, even to the years of
many generations. A fire devourth before
them, and behind them a flame burnth.
The land is as the garden of Eden before
them, and behind them a desolate
wilderness. Yay, nothing shall escape
them. Joel here
is equating the day of the Lord with
this coming army that would destroy
Jerusalem.
Who was that army? It was the Roman
army. This is the same verse that Peter
quotes on the day of Pentecost saying,
"Listen, repent and accept the Messiah
because if you do not, an army is
coming."
He's quoting Joel. an army is coming
that's going to destroy the this temple
and city because of your rejection of
the Messiah.
And so, beloved, this is the second day
of the Lord in the Bible. I said there
were three days of the Lord. Here is the
third day of the Lord. Let's go to the
book of First Thessalonians
5 2 and 3. The Bible says, "For
yourselves know perfectly that the day
of the Lord so cometh as a thief in the
night. For when they shall say peace and
safety, then sudden destruction cometh
upon them as travail upon a woman uh
with child, and they shall not escape."
First Thessalonians is speaking
literally about the second coming of
Jesus Christ, which is in fact the third
day of the Lord. Y'all put a one in the
chat if you're following. If this makes
sense so far, there are three days of
the Lord, the third being the actual
destruction of the world. Again in first
Thessalon 2 Thessalonians I'm sorry
chapter 2:2 the Bible says that you be
not soon shaken in mind or be troubled
neither by spirit nor by word nor by
letter as from us as that the day of
Christ is at hand. The day of the Lord
is the day of Christ. It is the time of
the second coming in second Peter
chapter 3 10-13. But the day of the Lord
will come as a thief in the night, in
the which the heavens shall pass away
with a great noise, and the elements
shall melt with fervent heat, and the
earth also, and the works that are
therein shall be burned up.
Nevertheless, we according to his
promise look for new heavens and a new
earth, wherein dwelleth righteousness.
And so
to recap,
the first day of the Lord, which the
pre-exilic prophets were all referring
to,
were not events to take place at the end
of time. Rather, they were events that
marked the end of the days of Jerusalem
by the Babylonian Empire.
After Jerusalem is destroyed, it is
years later rebuilt. Israel has a second
chance, but they begin to rebel against
God again. And new prophets rise up
warning of a second day of the Lord.
That second day of the Lord was
fulfilled in the Roman destruction of
Jerusalem in 70 AD.
But the Bible tells us there is a third
and final day of the Lord in the which
the heavens and the earth will will be
destroyed. That is a global event. This
is the second coming of Jesus Christ.
Now with that in mind, with that in
mind, what we want to ask now is a very
simple question.
Why did the first day of the Lord come
in the first place? That's the question.
That's the basis of this message today.
Why did the day of the Lord come in the
first place? Now, to answer that
question, it might seem like, oh, why
are we going here? But I need to take
you back to the book of Genesis. Back to
the book of Genesis.
And uh we're going to go we're going to
go in fact, you know what? Before we go
to the book of Genesis, let me just read
just just several more verses to you.
Revelation chapter 6 verse 16 and 17,
notice what it says here. uh the wicked
at the end of time cry out to the
mountains and rocks, saying, "Fall on
us, and hide us from the face of him
that siteth on the throne, and from the
wrath of the lamb,
for the great day of his wrath is come,
and who shall be able to stand." So, so
the question here is why the wrath of
the lamb? Why the wrath of the lamb? Let
me share with you the book of Hebrews
chapter 3:es 7-9.
So in Hebrews chapter 3 7-9, God is Paul
is speaking a and he's using the analogy
of the children of Israel in the Old
Testament as they were journeying to the
promised land. And I want you to notice
what he says here.
Wherefore, as the Holy Ghost saith,
Today, if you will hear his voice,
harden not your hearts, as in the
provocation, in the day of temptation in
the wilderness, when your fathers
tempted me, and proved me, and saw my
works 40 years. Wherefore I was grieved
with that generation, and said, they do
always heir in their heart, and they
have not always known my ways. So I
swear in my wrath they shall not enter
into my rest. Now guys, pause for a
second.
There are two options here. There is the
wrath of God and there is the rest of
God.
Those who who who do not enter into the
rest of God experience the wrath of God.
So when we just read that verse where
the wicked are crying out, "Hide us from
the wrath of the lamb." It is because
they did not enter into the rest of the
lamb. If y'all with me so far, put a two
in the chat. Pastor, we get it. The
wrath of God, the day of the Lord,
which equates with the wrath of God, is
reserved for those who entered not into
rest.
Okay. So, so with that in mind, now we
want to answer the question, well, why
was the first day of the Lord, the wrath
of the Lord? Why did that come about?
Why did Jerusalem get destroyed by the
Babylonian Empire? Why did God allow
that? And to answer that question, we
first need to go back to the book of
Genesis. We're going to go to Genesis
chapter 2. And I want you to note here
with me, Genesis chapter 2, verse one.
The Bible says here, "Thus the heavens
and the earth were finished, and all the
host of them. And on the seventh day,
God ended his work which he had made.
And he rested on the seventh day from
all his work which he had made. And God
blessed the seventh day and sanctified
it because at in it he had rested from
all his work which God created and
made." This is the first time in the
Bible we see God resting. And it is in
connection with the seventh day. God has
entered into rest. And this rest is
because he created the world in six
days. And he saw that everything was
good. And so the Sabbath was a sign that
man was was was submitted to the will of
God. That man and the earth everything
was good. Everything was good. So the
Sabbath was God's sign of of God's work,
of God's finished and completed work.
Now, we know that man sinned.
And when man sinned, uh, death and sin
and corruption came upon the earth. And
as we read through the book of Genesis,
even into the book of Exodus, we see
that the children of that that, uh, uh,
the children of Israel end up in
Egyptian captivity. And and then God is
going to deliver them out of captivity.
And then in Exodus 20, he gives them the
Sabbath uh, uh, as a nation. So he first
gave it in Genesis, but now he's
repeating this commandment. He's he's
he's letting the children of Israel who
had been in captivity for 400 years.
He's reminding them of the Sabbath. And
the text says in Exodus 20:8, "Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six
days shalt thou labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is a Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt
not do any work. Thou nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, nor thy manservant, nor
thy maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth the sea and all that in them is
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it. And so we see here God
reinstituting the Sabbath for his
people. Even in ex in Deuteronomy 5:12
and 13, we're told, "Keep the Sabbath
day to sanctify it as the Lord thy God
has commanded thee. Six days shalt thou
labor and do all thy work, but the
seventh day is a Sabbath of the Lord thy
God." It goes on to say in verse 15,
"And remember that thou was a servant in
the land of Egypt, and that the Lord thy
God brought thee out thence through a
mighty hand by a stretched out arm.
Therefore, the Lord thy God commanded
thee to keep the Sabbath day." So here
we find that God has commanded the
children of Israel, "Keep my Sabbath
for two reasons. Number one, it is a
reminder of what I did at the beginning
of creation. And number two, it is a
reminder that I delivered you out of
bondage.
In the book of Leviticus,
Moses now lays out
some blessings and some curses for the
children of Israel. If they obey,
they're going to be blessed. But if they
don't obey, they're going to be cursed.
And I want you to notice what Leviticus
chapter 26:1 says. It says, "You shall
make no idols, nor grave in image,
neither rear up a standing image,
neither shall you set up any image of
stone in your land to bow down unto it,
for I am the Lord your God." Verse two,
you shall keep my Sabbaths and reverence
my sanctuary. I am the Lord. Now watch
this. If you walk in my statutes and
keep my commandments and do them, then
will I give you rain in due season, and
the land shall yield her increase, and
the trees of the field shall yield their
fruit. And then he goes on to list all
these blessings, right? And now he's
going to come to the curses. And I want
you to notice
what Moses says in the curses if you
don't obey. In verse 33, it says, "I
will scatter you among the heathen and
will draw out a sword after you, and
your land shall be desolate and your
cities waste." Watch this. Then shall
the land enjoy her Sabbaths. As long as
it lith desolate, and you be in your
enemy's land, even then shall the land
rest and enjoy her Sabbath. Let me ask
you guys a question. According to
Leviticus 26, Moses is prophesying of
what would happen to the children of
Israel if this if they disobey God. And
the key reason that God gives for the
children of Israel going into captivity
and their land being desolate would be
because they did not let they did not
observe the Sabbath in their land. Is
everybody on the same page so far?
In fact, note with me notice with me 2
Chronicles 36 20 and 21. It says, "And
them that had escaped from the sword
carried he away to Babylon, where they
were servants to him and his sons until
the reign of the kingdom of Persia to
fulfill the word of the Lord by the
mouth of Jeremiah
until the land had enjoyed her Sabbaths.
For as long as she lay desolate, she
kept Sabbath to fulfill three score and
10 years." Do y'all see this? The first
day of the Lord where Babylon destroyed
Jerusalem was specifically
because the children of Israel refused
to honor the Sabbath. I'm not making
this up. Let's go to Jeremiah 17 27. But
if you will not hearken unto me to
hallow the Sabbath day, and to and not
to bear a burden, and enter in at the
gates of Jerusalem on the Sabbath day,
then will I kindle a fire in the gates
thereof, and it shall devour the palaces
of Jerusalem, and it shall not be
quenched.
That's pretty straightforward, you guys.
The reason Jerusalem was set on fire by
Babylon was specifically because they
had rejected the Sabbath.
In fact, Jeremiah 66:1 19
here, O earth, behold, I will bring evil
upon this people, even the fruit of
their thoughts, because they have not
hearkened unto my words, nor to my law,
but rejected it. In fact, in fact, as if
it couldn't be any more plain, I want
we're going somewhere with this. So,
please listen carefully.
In the book of Ezekiel chapter 20,
beginning with verse 12, the Bible says,
in fact, you know what? Let's start with
verse 6.
Ezekiel says, "In that day that I lift
up my hand," Ezekiel wrote this rather,
I should say, "In the day that I lift up
my hand unto them to lifted up my hand
unto them to bring them forth of the
land of Egypt, into a land that I had
aspired for them, flowing with milk and
honey, which is the glory of all lands."
Then said I unto them, "Cast ye away
every man the abomination of his eyes,
and defile not yourself with the idols
of Egypt. I am the Lord your God." But
they rebelled against me and would not
hearken unto me. They did not every man
cast away the abomination of their eyes.
Neither did they forsake the idols of
Egypt. Then I said, I will pour out my
fury unto them to accomplish my anger
against them in the midst of the land of
Egypt. Let's keep reading. But I brought
for my name's sake, that it should not
be polluted before the heathen, among
whom they were, in whose sight I made
myself known unto them in bringing them
forth out of the land of Egypt.
Wherefore I caused them to go forth out
of the land of Egypt, and brought them
into the wilderness, and I gave them my
statutes, and showed them my judgments,
which if a man do, he he shall live in
them. Moreover, also I gave them my
Sabbaths to be a sign between me and
them, that they might know that I am the
Lord that sanctified them. Watch this.
But the house of Israel rebelled against
me in the wilderness. They walked not in
my statutes, and they despised my
judgments, which if a man do, he shall
live in them, and my Sabbaths they
greatly polluted. Then I said, I would
pour my fury upon them in the wilderness
to consume them. But I wrought for my
name's sake, that it should not be
polluted.
Yet also I lifted up my hand in the
wilderness, that I would not that I
would not bring them into the land which
I had given them, flowing with milk and
honey, which is the glory of all lands.
It goes on, beloved, because they
despised my judgments and walked not in
my statutes, but polluted my Sabbaths,
for their heart went after their idols.
Neither mine I spared them from
destroying them, neither did I make an
end of them in the wilderness. Verse 20.
But I said unto the children of children
in the wilderness, walk not in the
statutes of your father, neither observe
their judgments, nor defile yourselves
with their idols. I am the Lord your
God. Walk in my statutes and keep my
judgments and do them. And hallow my
Sabbath, and they shall be a sign
between me and you. Notwithstanding, the
children of Israel rebelled against me.
They walked not in my statutes, neither
kept my judgments to do them. Which of a
man do he shall live in them? They
polluted my Sabbaths.
You guys,
how many times does he say it? The
reason the children of Israel went into
captivity is because they rejected, they
polluted the Sabbath of the Lord.
This is the reason for the first day of
the Lord. In Isaiah 58 verse one and
two, the Bible literally says, "Cry
aloud, spare not, lift up thy voice like
a trumpet, and show my people their
transgression and the house of Jacob
their sins." And he's going on telling
them about their sins. And then he
begins to tell them that the Sabbath
which God had given them was not to be
observed in any it was not to be
forgotten and was not just a day for
them to do whatever they wanted to. But
it says it was a day listen to this. Is
not this the fast I have chosen to loose
the bands of wickedness to undo the
heavy burdens and to let the oppressed
go free and that you break every yoke?
Is it not to deal thy bread to the
hungry, and that thou bring the poor
that are cast out into thy house? When
thou seest the naked, that thou cover
him, and when and you hide not yourself
from your own flesh? And if you draw out
your soul to the hungry, and satisfy the
afflicted soul, then shall thy light
rise in obscurity, and thy darkness
shall be as the noon day. If you turn
away your foot from the Sabbath, from
doing your pleasure on my holy day, the
entire chapter of Isaiah 58 is rebuking
the children of Israel for not correctly
observing the command that God had given
them. And as a result, listen to me now
everybody,
the day of the Lord came upon Israel
because they refused to observe the day
of the Lord. Let me pause.
Let me pause.
The day of the Lord
came upon Jerusalem
because they refused
the day of the Lord.
In other words, the day of the Lord, a
day of wrath, came upon Jerusalem
because they rejected the day of the
Lord, a day of rest. They rejected the
rest and therefore experienced the
wrath. You got two options, beloved, is
what I'm trying to tell you.
The Israel had two options. They could
either honor the day of the Lord, the
day of rest, or face the day of the
Lord, the day of wrath. And so now that
we see that the first day of the Lord
came about as a result of the children
of Israel's rejection of the day of the
Lord, the Sabbath.
That sets the stage for our second
question.
Our second question is going to be,
well, what reason pray tell, did the
second day of the Lord happen?
I'm glad you asked. Let's find out.
When we go to the book of Nehemiah,
we find that Nehemiah who lives after
the destruction of Jerusalem by Babylon,
he is part of the rebuilding of
Jerusalem. And Nehemiah is trying to
make sure that the children of Israel do
not make the same mistake they made
before,
ignoring the day of the Lord. That's
what they did. They ignored it.
Nehemiah 13:1 17 and 18 says this. Then
I contended with the nobles of Judah and
said unto them, "What evil thing is this
that you do and profane the Sabbath
day?"
I'm going to my verse 18 isn't up here,
so let me just read it in your hearing.
Did not our fathers thus? And did not
our God bring all this evil upon us and
upon this city? Yet you bring more wrath
upon Israel by profaining the Sabbath
rest. Note how the wrath of God,
Nehemiah was warning, listen, you
remember why we went into Babylon in the
first place. You remember why we
experienced the wrath of God? It's
because we rejected the rest of God. Are
you about to do this again? And so
Nehemiah is rebuking his own people. And
the Sabbath uh selling eventually stops.
And so from Nehemiah, we're now moving
forward. Remember, Nehemiah is post
destruction of Babylon. So the prophets
that come along with Nehemiah and
afterward begin to warn of this second
day of the Lord. Now why what is
Jerusalem doing or what have they done?
They're obviously not obeying the word
of God again which is why these prophets
are coming on the scene warning of this
day of the Lord. Now let's fast forward
to just some years before 70 AD. We're
going to go 40 40ome years before 70 AD
to when Jesus the Messiah comes.
In in excuse me in Daniel chapter 9 in
verse 26 there is a prophecy given of
the time of Jesus's coming. Daniel 9:26
it says this. And after three score and
two weeks shall Messiah be cut off but
not for himself. And the people of the
prince that shall come shall destroy the
city and the sanctuary. This is that
second day of the Lord, y'all.
And the end thereof shall be with a
flood, and unto the end of the war,
desolations are determined.
What is it
that brought the wrath of God upon
Jerusalem the second time?
Let's find out.
We're going to go to Mark chapter 3:1.
In Mark 3:1, the Bible says, "And he
entered again into the synagogue, and
there was a man there which had a
withered hand, and they watched him
whether he would heal him on the Sabbath
day, that they might accuse him." Now,
let me pause for a second here.
as a result of the children of Israel's
first day of the Lord, Babylon, right?
The destruction of Jerusalem by Babylon,
because they rejected the Sabbath,
because they forgot the Sabbath
after the destruction of Babylon and
after their rebuilding of their city and
temple,
they began to go the exact opposite.
They began to put rules
upon the Sabbath that you can't find in
the Bible. They began to become so
stringent and so strict on the Sabbath
that it is almost as though they
produced another Sabbath that wasn't in
the Bible.
They had rules on the Sabbath and and
and the way they treated the sab this
Sabbath was so was so uh rigid that it
was as it though as it were a totally
different Sabbath
to the point that by the time Jesus
comes on the scene they're watching
Jesus to see if he will heal on the
Sabbath to accuse him of breaking the
Sabbath.
You can't find thou shalt not healed on
the Sabbath anywhere in the Bible. You
can't find it. But they made that rule
up. So let's keep reading.
It says, "And he saith unto the man
which had the withered hand, stand
forth. And he saith unto them, is it
lawful to do good on the Sabbath days or
to do evil, to save life or to kill?"
But they held their peace. And when they
had when he had looked around about upon
them with anger, being grieved for the
hardness of their hearts, he saith unto
the man, Stretch forth thine hand. And
he stretched it out. And his hand was
restored whole as the other. And the
Pharisees went forth, and straightway
took counsel with the Herodians against
him, how they might destroy him. Now,
here's what I need y'all to notice.
This is Mark chapter 3.
This is very early in the ministry of
Jesus.
In fact,
it was this event
that planted the seed for the Pharisees
to kill Jesus.
This is the first time in the Bible that
the leaders say Jesus must die. And
beloved, that is significant because
they put Jesus, the Lord of the Sabbath,
to death in the name of the Sabbath.
Think about that for a moment, y'all.
The reason they put Jesus to death was
because they claimed that Jesus had
broken the Sabbath.
Let that sink in.
The seed,
the event
that led to their rejection of the
Messiah
was that he had broken their
misunderstanding
of the Sabbath.
Go with me to John 5:1-3. After this,
there was a feast of the Jews. And Jesus
went up to Jerusalem. Now there is at
Jerusalem by the sheep's market a pool
which is called in the Hebrew tongue
Bethesda, which h having five porches.
In these lay a great multitude of
impotent folk, and blind and halt
withered, waiting for the moving of the
waters. And and for an angel went down
at a certain season in the pool, and
troubled the water. Whosoever then
first, who whosoever then first after
the troubling of the water stepped in,
was made whole of whatever disease he
had. And a certain man was there, which
had an infirmity 30 and 8 years. When
Jesus saw him lie, so he couldn't walk,
he knew that he had been long time in
this case. He saith unto him, "Wilt thou
be made whole?" The impotent man
answered him, "Sir, I have no man when
the water is troubled to put me into the
pool, but when I'm coming, another
stepeth down before me." Jesus saith
unto him, "Rise up, take up, rise, take
up your bed, and walk." And immediately
the man was made whole, and took up his
bed, and walked. And on the same day was
the Sabbath. The Jews therefore said
unto him that was cured, "It is the
Sabbath day. It is not lawful of thee to
carry thy bed." Again, no rule in the
Bible. None. He answered them, and said,
He that made me whole, the same said
unto me, Take up thy bed and walk. Then
asked him, What man is that is that
which said unto thee, Take up thy bed
and walk? And he and he that was healed
wis not who it was. For Jesus had
conveyed himself away a multitude being
in that place.
Afterward Jesus findeth him in the
temple and saith unto him, Behold, thou
art made whole. Sin no more, lest the
worst thing come upon thee. The man
departed and told the Jews, it was Jesus
which made him whole. Watch this. And
therefore did the Jews persecute Jesus
and sought to slay him because he had
done these things on the Sabbath day.
Beloved, please understand this.
The thing that set the Jewish nation in
motion to kill Jesus
was the Sabbath.
It was the Sabbath. This is absolutely
mind-blowing, beloved.
Because as we look at that other
example,
at that other example, notice with me
the book of Luke, I'm sorry, not the
book of Luke, the book of John, chapter
9, verse 1 and 2. And as Jesus passed
by, he saw a man which was blind from
his birth. And his disciples asked him,
saying, "Master, who did this sin? The
man or his parents that he was born
blind?"
Jesus answered, "Neither has this man
sinned, nor his parents, but that the
works of God should be made manifest in
him. I must work the works of him that
sent me, while it is day, the night
cometh when no man can work. As long as
I'm in the world, I am the light of the
world." And when he had thus spoken, he
spat on the ground, and made clay of the
spittle, and anointed the eyes of the
blind man with clay, and said unto him,
"Go wash in the pool of Sylum, which is
by interpretation sent." He went his
way, therefore, and washed, and came
seeing. The neighbors therefore, and
they which before him had seen that he
was blind, said, "Is not he this he that
sat and begged?" Some said, "This is
he?" Others said, "He is like him." But
he said, "I am he." Therefore said they
unto him, "How were thine eyes opened?"
He answered and said, "A man that is
called Jesus, made clay, and anointed
mine eyes, and said unto me, go to the
pool of Sil, and wash, and I went and
washed, and I received my sight." Watch
this. Then said they unto him, "Where is
he?" He said, "I know not." They brought
to the Pharisees him that a four time
was blind. And it was the Sabbath day
when Jesus made the clay and opened his
eyes. Then again the Pharisees also
asked him how how he had received his
sight. He said unto them, he put clay
upon mine eyes and washed and I do see.
Therefore the Pharisees said of some of
the Pharisees said, "This man of is not
of God because he keepeth not the
Sabbath day." All right, y'all.
They killed the Lord of the Sabbath,
the creator of the Sabbath over a
counterfeit version of the Sabbath.
And as a result,
think about this now.
On that Friday evening that they kill
Jesus,
they walk away to keep the Sabbath.
When in fact in killing Jesus, the Lord
of the Sabbath, they had broken the
Sabbath in the most egregious way.
They wanted to put Jesus to death to
spare their nation because Jesus was a
Sabbath breaker. And yet in putting
Jesus to death over the Sabbath, they
had in essence broken the Sabbath which
in essence brought about the second day
of the Lord upon them.
Jerusalem was destroyed by Rome because
Jerusalem rejected Jesus, put him to
death, and then thought they were
keeping the Sabbath.
Put the Lord of the Sabbath to death.
And in so doing,
they had broken the very essence and
spirit of the Sabbath. You see, let me
break something down to you.
Jesus healed
a crippled man
on the Sabbath,
a man with a withered hand on the
Sabbath,
and a blind man on the Sabbath.
And and I want you to note, beloved, all
those healings represented something. In
Ecclesiastes 9:10, the Bible says,
"Whatsoever thy hand findth to do, do it
with thy might, for there is no work,
nor device, nor wisdom, nor knowledge in
the grave, whether thou goest." It's as
though the healing of the hand was to
was to in essence show that Christ came
to do a greater healing, came to help us
to see what the work of God is, how to
do the work of God. He healed a crippled
man. The Bible says in Psalms 119:105,
"Thy word is a lamp unto my feet and a
light unto my path." It's as though in
healing the crippled man, God, Jesus was
showing that he has come to make us able
to walk in the path of righteousness. He
healed a blind man. The Bible says,
"Open thou mine eyes." Psalm 119:18,
"Open thy mine eyes that I may behold
wondrous things out of thy law." It's as
though Jesus was trying to open the eyes
of the blind so that they could see the
light of the world.
In fact, beloved,
the very purpose of the Sabbath was to
loose the bonds of wickedness, to let
the captives go free. And the fact that
they killed Jesus
over his correct observation of the
Sabbath shows that they in essence had
rejected the Sabbath in a different way
than they had done back under the first
day of the Lord. They had rejected the
Sabbath by putting rules and regulations
and being strict about rules and
regulations God never applied to the
Sabbath. So much so that they killed the
Lord of the Sabbath. They had instituted
a counterfeit Sabbath and enforced it
with death.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you're
following so far because beloved, all of
this
sets up our third and final question,
which is
if the first day of the Lord came as a
result of the children of Israel
forgetting the Sabbath and the second
day of the Lord came as a result of the
children of Israel implementing a
counterfeit Sabbath so strenuously and
enforced that they put the Lord of the
Sabbath to death over that counterfeit
Sabbath.
The final question is
what brings about the third day of the
Lord?
That's a fair question, isn't it?
That would seem like a logical question.
What is it that brings about the third
and final day of the Lord? And beloved,
may I suggest to you that if the first
day of the Lord came as a result of
forgetting the Sabbath and the second
day of the Lord came as a result of a
counterfeit version of the Sabbath, then
could it be possible that the third day
of the Lord comes about as a combination
of the two? Could it be that the third
day of the Lord comes about as a result
of one forgetting God's true Sabbath and
two implementing a counterfeit one
with the force
of death behind it in the name of Jesus
in the name of God.
Come with me to Revelation 14:12 where
the Bible speaks about an end time
people who have the patience of the
saints. Here they the Bible says that
keep the commandments of God and the
faith of Jesus. We know that at the end
of time according to Revelation chapter
14:12 that there will be a
commandmentkeeping people of God. We
know that the text says that
might that have something to do with end
time events. The Bible says in
Revelation 12:1 17, the dragon was wroth
and went to was wroth with the woman and
went to make war with the remnant of her
seed which keep the commandments of God
and have the testimony of Jesus Christ.
Could it be possible, beloved, that at
the end of time that Satan will be out
to try to destroy the people who are
actually keeping the commandments of
God, not forgetting it like ancient
Israel and not altering it and coming up
with new rules and regulations that God
never commanded as happened in the in
the time of Jesus. Could it be possible
that the dragon is out to destroy those
people to remove that witness of a
people who actually do what God says to
do? Who actually remember what God says
to remember? In fact, in Revelation 14 6
and 7, the Bible says, "I saw another
angel fly in the midst of heaven, having
the everlasting gospel to preach unto
them that dwell on the earth, and to
every nation, kindred, tongue, and
people, saying with a loud voice, fear
God, and give glory to him, for the hour
of his judgment is come, and worship him
that made heaven and earth and the sea
and the fountains of waters." Beloved,
please be aware that this is an end time
message that goes to the entire world.
And the last portion of that sentence is
lifted directly out of the fourth
commandment, which tells us that God is
the one who created the heaven, the
earth, and the sea, and all that in them
is. In other words, beloved, that angel
that is flying in the midst of heaven
with the everlasting gospel is coming
with a message, a warning
to avoid the same mistake that ancient
Israel made before the first day of the
Lord and before the second day of the
Lord, that there is coming a third day
of the Lord. And those who refuse the
rest of the Lord
will face the wrath of the Lord.
This is absolutely crucial to
understand. Beloved,
in Revelation 7:1, the Bible says,
"After these things, I saw four angels
standing on the four corner of the of
the earth, holding the four winds of the
earth, that the wind should not blow on
the earth, nor on the sea, nor on any
tree. And I saw another angel ascending
from the east, having the seal of the
living God, or the sign of the living
God." Remember, we read back in Ezekiel
that the Sabbath was the sign between
God and his people.
Beloved, you can't make this up.
That which brought about the first day
of the Lord and the second day of the
Lord will also bring about the third day
of the Lord. And it is interesting
beloved that that as the first day of
the Lord occurred in connection with
Babylon and the second day of the Lord
occurred in connection with Rome at the
end of time we have a power a power
called mystery Babylon that is symbolic
of Rome in a spiritual context.
Revelation 17:5 says and upon her
forehead was a name written mystery
Babylon the great the mother of harlots
and abominations of the earth. In the
Bible, a woman when used symbolically,
particularly in the book of Revelation,
is likened unto a church. So here,
beloved, in Revelation chapter 17, what
we have is a church being described as
Babylon,
but is also Roman in nature.
If we were to go back to the book of
Daniel 7:25, this same power is
described as a little horn. The Bible
says, "He shall speak great words
against the most high and shall wear out
or persecute the saints of the most high
and think to change
times and laws, and they shall be given
into his hand until a time, times, and
half a time." And beloved, there is one
power that came out of Rome and that the
Bible identifies as mystery Babylon.
This is a power, a church that has both
forgotten
God's Sabbath day and also implemented a
counterfeit version of it and said, "Do
this. Remember this." of whom the Bible
says the time is coming where they will
enforce this counterfeit by decree.
And just as Jesus was put to death
because he refused
to observe a counterfeit Sabbath.
That is the reason Jesus died.
He refused to observe a counterfeit
Sabbath. In the same way, this power
described in Daniel 7:25 will do the
same.
Here is a little bit of history for you.
Two simple quotes.
The first one is from Priest Brady
reported in the Elizabeth Elizabeth, New
Jersey news on March 18th, 1903. And
here's what he says. It is well to
remind the Presbyterians, Baptists,
Methodists, and all other Christians
that the Bible does not support them
anywhere in their observance of Sunday.
Sunday is an institution of the Roman
Catholic Church, and those who observe
the day observe a commandment of the
Catholic Church. How about this one? Our
Sunday visitor, February 5th, 1950.
Protestants accept Sunday rather than
Saturday as the day for public worship
after the Catholic Church. not Jesus.
After the Catholic Church made the
change, but the Protestant mind does not
seem to realize that in observing
Sunday, they are accepting the authority
of the spokesman for the church, the
pope.
Beloved, I want you to understand
that the Christian world today, not only
Catholic, but Protestants as well, have
by and large not only embraced the error
that brought about the first day of the
Lord, forgetting God's true Sabbath, but
they've embraced the error that brought
about the second day of the Lord,
embracing a counterfeit Sabbath
that God never spoke.
And the time is coming where that
counterfeit Sabbath will be enforced. In
fact, look in the Christian world today
and you will see talk of bringing of of
enforcing Sunday worship or legalizing
Sunday worship. You see it happening now
in this movement to bring the ten
commandments to schools all over America
because one of those commandments, the
fourth, has been forgotten
first day of the Lord and replaced with
a counterfeit second day of the Lord.
And God is looking for a people who at
the end of time will choose to obey God
rather than man.
Now come on, I got to show you one more
thing. And then we're going to wrap this
message up. Remember back in Hebrews how
we read there, "Let us therefore fear,
lest the promise being left us of
entering into his rest, any of you
should seem to come short of it. For
unto us was the gospel preached as well
as unto them. But the word preached did
not profit them, not being mixed with
faith in them that heard it. For we
which believe do enter into that rest,
as he said, as I have sworn in my wrath,
if they shall enter into my rest,
although the works were finished from
the foundation of the world. Beloved, I
want you to understand that just as
those who on the first day of the Lord
experienced the wrath of the Lord
because they rejected the rest of the
Lord, that is the Sabbath, they were
they experienced the day of the Lord
because they rejected the day of the
Lord. So in the second day of the Lord,
they experienced the wrath of the Lord
because they rejected the rest of the
Lord. They experienced the day of the
Lord because they refused to rightly
honor the day of the Lord. So at the end
of time, beloved, those who experience
the wrath of the day of the Lord, it is
because they have rejected the the
Hebrews says there remainth therefore a
rest to the people of God.
That rest is in allowing Jesus to come
into you and give you rest from the
works of your flesh. Rest from
lawlessness, rest from Sabbath breaking,
rest from adultery, rest from murder,
rest from lying, rest from killing, rest
from covetousness, rest from having
other gods. That's what the rest is
about. And that rest
does not negate the commandments of God.
The devil was able to lead the to lead
those under the first day of the Lord to
say, "Ah, the Sabbath, we don't need to
keep it." He was able to lead those
under the second day of the Lord to say,
"Hey, we're going to set up a
counterfeit version of the Sabbath and
be really, really stringent with that
one."
Beloved, so he's seeking to deceive
people today
in two ways.
The Sabbath, oh, that's done away with.
That was for the Jews. And in the
meantime, we're just going to create a
new Sabbath. And maybe we'll call it the
Sabbath, and maybe we won't. But it'll
be something that we enforce
stringently.
Y'all know the rule. Y'all know the
tradition.
Let me show you before we close. You
have to see this in Nehemiah chapter 13.
The Bible says, "In those days I saw I
in Judah some treading wine presses on
the Sabbath and bringing in sheav and
latting asses as also wine, grapes, and
figs, all manner of burden which they
brought into R into Jerusalem on the
Sabbath day. And I testified against
them in the day which in wherein they
sold victuals.
There dwelt men of Ty also therein,
which brought fish, and all manner of
wear, and sold on the Sabbath unto the
children of Israel, and in Jerusalem.
Then I contended with the nobles of
Judah, and said unto them, "What evil
thing is this that you do, and profane
the Sabbath day? Did not your fathers
thus? And did not our God bring all the
evil upon us upon this city? Yet you
bring more wrath upon Israel by
profaining the Sabbath?" Watch this. And
it came to pass that when the gates of
Jerusalem began to be dark before the
Sabbath, I commanded that the gates
should be shut and charged that they
should not be opened till after the
Sabbath. And some of my servants set I
at the gates that there should no burden
be brought on the Sabbath day. So the
merchants and the settlers of all kind
of wear lodged without Jerusalem once or
twice. Then I testified against him and
said unto them, why lodge you about the
wall? If you do so again, I will lay
hands on you from that time forth. Came
they no more on the Sabbath. Why is this
significant?
Because beloved, the Bible tells us in
Revelation 21 27 that there shall in no
wise enter into the city anything that
defileth, nor whatsoever workketh
abomination or maketh a lie, but they
which are written in the Lamb's book of
life. Revelation 20 uh Revelation uh 18
tells us, "For all nations have drunk of
the wine of the wrath of her
fornication, and the kings of the earth
have committed fornication with her. And
the merchants of the earth," Pause for a
second, y'all, the merchants were the
ones who were outside of Jerusalem who
did not come in because they did not
honor the Sabbath. In the very same way,
beloved, at the end of time,
in that new Jerusalem, the gates are
only open to those who obeyed the
commandments of God. The merchants
do not get to enter.
Those who are more concerned with making
a living than keeping the Those who are
more concerned with with with with
providing for themselves and doing their
own thing.
Those are the ones
that don't enter into the city.
Our closing text is this, beloved.
Revelation 22:14-5 says, "Blessed are
they that do his commandments, that they
may have right to the tree of life, and
may enter in through the gates into the
city, for without are dogs and
sorcerers, and whoreongers, and
murderers, and idoltors, and whosoever
loveth and maketh a lie." Beloved, my
appeal to you today is very specific.
Do not make the mistake that was made
in the first day of the Lord. Do not
make the mistake that was made in the
second day of the Lord.
Keep the commandments of God.
Live by the testimony of Jesus.
Accept the rest of God. Accept the day
of the Lord so that you do not have to
fear the day of the Lord. Accept the
rest of God so you do not have to
experience the wrath of God. He has
shown it to us again and again in
scripture.
Let us not be blind.
Let us not be ignorant.
Let us not be willful
in disobedience to God.
Let us keep his commandments. As he has
said, if you love me, keep my
commandments. And beloved, we will have
right to the tree of life. If it's your
desire to say, Lord, yes, I want to keep
your commandments. I don't want to make
the mistake that was made under the
first day of the Lord, and I don't want
to make the same mistake that was made
under the second day of the Lord. I want
to I want to experience your rest so
that I do not face your wrath.
I don't want to face the wrath of God,
but he invites me into the rest of God.
If that's your desire, put a one in the
chat as we pray. Heavenly Father, thank
you. Thank you for speaking to us today.
Lord, thank you for showing us this
pattern
of the way you worked to redeem and to
save your people. But how they continue
to reject either by going by forgetting
or becoming so uh uh
caught up in a wrong form of worship
that in both ways they ultimately
rejected the Sabbath and its true
meaning.
Please Lord, help us to obey your
commandments, to not be led to the right
or to the left, but to obey your word as
you have written it. Write your law upon
our hearts and in our minds. And Lord,
seal us so that we may be ready for you
to come again. In Jesus name we pray.
Amen. And amen. May God bless you as you
continue to worship. May God bless you
as you continue to study and make the
word the supreme authority in your life.
And may this message uh reach and touch
your heart and put you and set you on a
path closer to Jesus is my prayer in
Jesus name. Amen. Amen. God bless you.
>> Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch. church. We are not just
here for Sabbath service. We have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health, physical health, weekly prayer
service, financial health, and proving
the existence of God. It is our desire
that our programming will continue to
bless you. Please continue to pray for
us as we fulfill God's mission to go
into all the world with the gospel of
Jesus Christ.
[Music]